根据真实故事改编
马塞诸塞州 波士顿 1976年
波 士 顿 警 察 局
十 一 区
聚焦
字幕由SSK字幕组倾情译制
仅供学习，勿用于商，转载请注明出处，版权归片方所有
官网：www.sskzmz.com
更多内容可以关注我们的新浪微博
《波士顿环球报》办公楼  2001年7月
艾琳・麦克纳马拉 著
相似的套路
主教伯纳德・劳对此不予置评
神父约翰・J・吉欧根是嫌疑人
因1987年性侵索赔
波特站上马塞诸塞州法庭
波士顿
总教区
遭指控
神父
性虐待
教义问答书
注：英文中prey和pray发音相似
原句出自非洲古谚语“抚养一个孩子需要全村的努力”
休病假
未分配
任职中
治疗中心
佩尔顿街 276号房
孩子们
不要接近佩尔顿街的276号房
也不要接近住在里面的人
波特案受害者的律师称同地区
还有其他20位神父受到起诉
距离截止日还有二十一天零四小时
距离截止日还有八天零二小时
你的线人怎么样了
快到时候了
本
在2002年 聚焦小组披露了将近600起此类丑闻
在波士顿总教区内有249位神父和兄弟会成员被公开指控性骚扰
波士顿的幸存者预计超过1000人
2002年12月 劳红衣主教从波士顿总教区辞职
他被重新任命去罗马的圣母玛利亚大教堂任职
那是全世界最高级的罗马天主教教堂之一
重大的丑闻在以下地区被揭露：
翻译 Bunny Levi Mark 夏洛 苦瓜
一校 小P  总校 Peach  时轴 Bunny
特效 一只蠢喵 压制 hhjie  总监 Luke
怎样了
How's that going?
那个妈妈在痛哭 那个舅舅气得跳脚
The mother's bawling and the uncle's pissed off.
-她没有结婚吗 -离婚了 带着四个孩子
- She's not married? - Divorced with four kids.
我猜 之前都是神父在帮忙
I guess father was helping out.
这也算帮忙
Helping out?
嘿 伯克先生 他们在后面和主教谈话
Hey, Mr. Burke, they're in back talking to the bishop.
-神父呢 -我们让他待在休息室
- And father? - We put him in the break room.
-有媒体来吗 -有个《公民报》的记者 但我们打发他走了
- Any press? - Some guy from the citizen, but we sent him away.
-暂时还没大报的人来 -继续保持
- None of the big papers. - Let's keep it that way.
-那是谁 -助理地方检察官
- Who's that? - Assistant da.
传讯的时候就很难挡住那些媒体了
It's gonna be hard to keep the papers away from the arraignment.
哪会有什么传讯
What arraignment?
你告诉吉欧根神父我很快就好
You can tell father Geoghan I won't be much longer.
你看 希拉
Now, Sheila, you know
你知道教会在这个社区做了多少善事
what good work the church does in the community.
我以个人名义担保
I give you my personal guarantee
我会让神父离开这个教区
that I'm going to take father out of the parish
这种事不会再有第二次
and this will never happen again.
-我们还需要一会儿 保罗 -好的 神父
- We'll just be another moment, Paul. - Of course, father.
希拉 现在我以个人名义保证
Now, Sheila, I'm going to give you my personal guaran...
失去一位好记者的感觉总是不好受
Losing a good reporter is always tough.
但失去一位精英中的精英
But losing one of our best--
额 我尽可能准确地描述
uh, well, to put it as eloquently as I can,
那感觉真的十分蛋疼
it's a real kick in the ass.
但罗比和斯图尔特的
But Robby here has known
交情比你们大多数人活得还要久
Stewart longer than most of you have been alive,
所以接下来就让他来说说吧
so I'll hand it off to him.
-罗比 -噢 谢谢 本
- Robby. - Oh, well, thanks, Ben.
其实不想谢你
I think.
尽管对你所说的我的资历辈分 我并不尽认同
Although I take issue with your reference to my seniority,
但不可否认 斯图尔特的离开对我来说特别痛苦
I will say that Stewart's departure is especially painful for me.
因为 斯图尔特
Because for-- what, Stewart?
有二十年了吧
Twenty years now?
斯图尔特一直
Stewart's been more than
勤勤恳恳地把钱输在扑克桌上
willing to part with his money at the poker table.
而我还有个大学生要养
And I've got a kid in college.
-嗯 但我还会继续玩的 -噢 那问题解决了
- Yeah, but I'm gonna keep playing. - Oh, problem solved.
那就祝你一切顺利了
Godspeed then.
斯图尔特 我觉得
Now, Stewart, I find the timing
你离开的时间特别烦人
of your departure disconcerting.
角落的办公室空了
The corner office sits empty.
新编辑周一才到
The new editor arrives on Monday.
所以抱歉 兄弟 但我得问你
So I'm sorry, buddy, but I gotta ask ya,
你到底是怎么办事的
what the hell do you know?
蛋糕怎么样
How's the cake?
很好吃啊
It's really good.
-你留着不吃吗 -不 这是给麦克的
- Are you saving yours? - Nah, it's for Mike.
-我吃不了这些东西 吃了我情绪不好 -我知道
- I can never eat at those things. They kind of depress me. - I know.
-你看到华盛顿的数据了吗 -看了 很有意思
- Did you see the numbers from Washington? - Yeah. Very interesting.
我也觉得
I think so too.
我不是在问你警察局是不是在撒谎 我知道他们在撒谎
I'm not asking if the pd's lying. I know they're lying.
我要问的就是 这背后是谁在指使
All I'm asking-- who's behind it?
嗯哼 行 我知道了 你不想谈
Uh-huh. Okay, I get it. You don't want to talk.
不 丹 我不是生气 我是饿了
No, Dan. I'm not mad, I'm hungry.
我讲了那么久 还没吃午饭呢
I've been talking so long I didn't eat lunch.
所以我要去找点吃的了
So I'm going to get something to eat.
正好给你一小时决定
That'll give you an hour to decide
你到底要不要在站在正确的一方
whether you want to be on the right side of this
还是想像其他人一样读着我们的报道
or read about it like everybody else.
-再见 丹 -你觉得卡希尔手上有料吗
- Bye, Dan. - You think Cahill has something?
可能吧 我只是觉得我们不该做这个故事
Maybe. I just don't think the story's for us.
-本喜欢 -是啊 它还行
- Ben likes it. - Yeah, it's not bad.
-只是不符合聚焦的风格 -什么不符合
- It's just not spotlight. - What's just not spotlight?
-警察局的数据 -那个数据的报道 感觉很站不住脚
- The pd numbers. - The numbers story. It feels thin.
噢 你让卡希尔开口了吗
Oh. You got Cahill to talk?
还没 但我会的
No. But I will.
很好 到时我们就知道站不站得住脚了
Good. Then we'll know if it's thin.
-楼上情况怎么样 -还不错
- How'd it go upstairs? - Okay.
-罗比发表了一场很赞的演讲 -毫无疑问
- Robby gave a good speech. - I'm sure he did.
我听说鲁宾和康奈尔
I heard Lubin and Connor
-要去《纽约时报》工作 -不是吧 真的吗
- are going to the Times. - Come on. Really?
他们在吸我们的血
They're leeching us.
他们从迈阿密派了个人过来 情况应该会好点
They're sending a guy from Miami to run things. That should help.
巴伦之前在波士顿待过吗
Has Baron even spent time in Boston?
我想他之前从没来过这里 我们应该给他买张地图
I don't think he's been here before. We should buy him a map.
-我在迈阿密的一个朋友说他裁了百分之十五的员工 -真棒
- A friend down in Miami said he cut 15% of the staff. - Great.
嘿 罗比 新上司过来裁员的吗
Hey, Robby. New boss coming in to make some cuts?
我不知道
I have no idea.
-你不是要和他坐下来谈吗 -是的
- Aren't you sitting down with him? - Yes, I am.
-是关于我们聚焦专栏吗 -我不知道 麦克
- So is it about spotlight? - I don't know, Mike.
但我知道本想要
But I do know that Ben
那个犯罪数据的报道
needs an answer on the crime numbers story.
我和你说 我真的觉得我们不该做这个故事
I'm telling you, I really don't think that story's for us.
-巴伦先生 -噢
- Mr. Baron. - Oh.
沃尔特・罗宾森 叫我罗比就行
Walter Robinson. Robby. Yeah.
-感谢你周末抽空与我见面 -十分乐意
- Thanks for taking the time out of your weekend. - My pleasure.
-谢谢 -不客气
- Appreciate it. - Pleasure.
-你在读什么 -额 《贝比鲁斯魔咒》
- What are you reading? - Uh, curse of the bambino.
啊 那是本好书
Ah, yeah. It's a great book.
对了 你安顿下来后
The globe has season tickets
《环球报》会有芬威球场的季票
at Fenway once you're settled in, by the way.
谢谢 其实 我不是很喜欢棒球
Thank you. To be honest, I'm-- I'm not much of a baseball fan.
我只是试着感受这个城市的氛围
I'm just trying to get a feel for the city.
噢 好吧
Oh. Yeah.
所以你是波士顿本地人吗
So you're originally from Boston?
是的 土生土长
I am. Born and raised, yeah.
新闻编辑部里很多人都是
A lot of the newsroom is from here.
感觉就好像是 一家本地报社
It really feels like a-- like a local paper in that way.
报纸被《纽约时报》收购后有改变这个感觉吗
And did that change at all after the paper was sold to the times?
没有 没 我觉得还不至于有这么大影响
No. No, I don't think that had a big impact.
很好
Good.
那么 额 你是聚焦小组的编辑
And, uh, you're an editor for the spotlight team?
我更倾向于把自己当做是一个球队教练 但 是的
I'd prefer to think of myself as player coach, but yes.
你熟悉聚焦吗
Are you familiar with spotlight?
不是很了解
No, not particularly.
好吧 我们是由四个人组成的调查小组
Well, we are a four-person investigative team.
我们隶属于本・布莱德利二世
We report to Ben bradlee Jr.,
我们工作保持绝对机密
and we keep our work confidential.
你们现在在跟进什么
What are you working on now?
我们刚完结一个假冒建筑公司的报道
We just put out a piece on a shoddy construction outfit,
现在我们只是在
and right now we're really
寻找有没有值得挖掘的故事
just trolling around for our next story.
这一般需要多长时间
How long does that typically take?
很难说 额 几个月吧
Hard to say. Uh, a couple months.
-几个月 -是的
- Couple months? - Yeah.
我们不想操之过急
We don't like to rush it.
我们一旦选定一个项目
Once we settle on a project,
我们会花上一年甚至更多的时间去调查
we can spend a year or more investigating it.
-有什么问题吗 -不一定
- Is that a concern? - Not necessarily.
嗯 但从我所了解的看来 阅读量正在下降
Um, but from what I understand, readership is down.
互联网侵入了各行各业 还有 额
Internet is cutting into the classified business and, uh,
我想我需要对这些事情严肃对待
I think I'm gonna need to take a hard look at things.
所以 你希望精简人员
So, you anticipate more cuts.
额 可以这么说
Uh, I think it's safe to assume so.
但是 额 我现在更关注的是 要如何让读者
But, uh, what I'm more focused on right now is finding a way to--
觉得这份报纸不可或缺
to make this paper essential to its readers.
我觉得它已经做到了
I like to think it already is.
好吧 我只是认为我们可以做得更好
Fair enough. I just think that we can do better.
-布莱德利先生 -嘿
- Mr. Bradlee. - Hey.
看到警察局的数据了 看起来很有趣
Saw the pd numbers. Looks interesting.
是啊 里面有点故事
Yeah, there's something there.
-你还需要多长时间 -额 再多一周
- How long do you need? - Uh, another week.
-你要去哪 -去开会啊
- Where are you going? - To the 10:30.
你什么时候也要开会了
Since when?
严格来说 我是个编辑
Well, technically, I am an editor.
严格来说而已 你和巴伦聊的怎么样
Technically. Your sit-down with baron go that well?
-我读不懂他这个人 -居然有你读不懂的人
- I couldn't get a read on him. - That's a first.
-那你呢 -他是个开心果啊
- How about you? - Well, he's a barrel of laughs.
-大家早上好 -那我们开始吧
- Morning, everyone. - Let's get started.
你想说几句吗 马蒂
Do you want to say something, Marty?
额 好的
Uh, sure.
额 大家好
Uh, hello.
额 大家应该都知道
Uh, as most of you know by now,
我叫马蒂・巴伦
my name is Marty baron.
我 很开心来到这里
I'm, uh, delighted to be here.
我们轮着说话的时候
Um, if you could tell me
如果你们能顺便说一下自己的名字就更好了
your name as we go around, that'd be helpful.
谢谢
Thank you.
好的 彼得
Okay. Peter?
彼得・卡内洛斯 来自《都市报》
Peter canellos, Metro.
我有个大故事要挖完了
I've got a major big dig closure.
-嘿 史蒂夫 -麦克
- Hey, Steve. - Mike.
嘿 昨晚的比赛很烂吧
Hey. Crappy game last night, huh?
是啊 他们的击球烂到爆了
Yeah, they can't hit worth a nickel.
嘿 听着 那个
Hey, listen, what's,
艾琳・麦克纳马拉在会议室里做什么
um-- what's Eileen McNamara doing in the 10:30?
-你需要点什么吗 麦克 -不 我只是好奇
- Do you need something, Mike? - No, just curious.
去别的地方好奇去 我还有事要做呢
Go be curious somewhere else. I got work to do.
-好吧 史蒂夫 再见了 -不送
- Okay, Steve. See ya. - Yeah.
看来佩德罗要到九月一号才会重回赛场
And it looks like Pedro's gonna be out till September 1.
吉米说他今年就会重新开始比赛
Jimmy says he'll be back this year,
但医生看起来没那么肯定
but the doc didn't seem so sure.
新英格兰爱国者队的开幕赛是什么时候
When's the Pats opener?
大家都说过了吗
Is that, uh, everyone?
-是的 -好的 谢谢
- Yes, that's it. - Okay. Good. Thank you.
大家读过艾琳・麦克纳马拉这周的专栏了吗
Uh, did everyone read Eileen McNamara's column this weekend?
是那个吉欧根的案子吗
That's the geoghan case?
是的 后续报道如何
Yeah. What's the folo on that?
那就是个专栏 你想要怎么样的后续报道
It-- it's a column. What kind of folo were you thinking?
额 很显然 三十年来 这位神父
Uh, well, apparently this priest molested kids
在六个不同教区都猥亵过儿童
in six different parishes over the last 30 years,
而受害者的律师 额
and the attorney for the victims, Mr., uh--
-加拉贝迪安先生 -谢谢 艾琳
- Garabedian. - Thanks, Eileen.
加拉贝迪安先生说劳红衣主教
Mr. Garabedian says cardinal Law
十五年前就发现了他的行径 却无所作为
found out about it 15 years ago and did nothing.
我觉得那个律师是个怪人
I think that attorney's a bit of a crank.
教会也否认了这一说法
And the church dismissed the claim.
公说公有理 婆说婆有理
He said, she said.
不管加拉贝迪安先生是不是怪人
Whether Mr. Garabedian is a crank or not,
他说他有文件可以证明主教知道此事
he says he has documents that prove the cardinal knew.
据我所知 这些文件是密封的
As I understand it, those documents are under seal.
好吧 但事实就是事实 波士顿一位神父虐待八十位儿童
Okay, but the fact remains, a Boston priest abused 80 kids,
我们有一位律师声称可以证明劳知道此事
we have a lawyer who says he can prove Law knew about it,
而我们过去六个月里也就写了 两篇报道
and we've written all of, uh, two stories in the last six months.
我认为这个故事对于一个本地报纸来说十分重要
This strikes me as an essential story to a local paper.
我想我们至少要浏览一遍那些文件
I think at the very least we have to go through those documents.
你想怎么做呢
How would you like to do that?
额 我不清楚这里的法律
Well, uh, I don't know what the laws are here,
但在佛罗里达 我们会上法庭
but in Florida, we would go to court.
你想要控告教会吗
You want to sue the church?
严格来说 我们不会控告教会
Technically, we wouldn't sue the church.
我们只是提出动议 要求公开密封文件
We'd file a motion to lift the seal on those documents.
教会会理解为我们要控告他们
The church will read that as us suing them.
大家都会这么认为
So will everybody else.
谢谢告知
Good to know.
-新官上任三把火啊 -这说得真没错
- Gutsy call for the first day. - That's one word for it.
你觉得这会有什么后果
How do you think that's gonna play down front?
我想吉尔曼会很担心
I think Gilman's gonna shit a brick.
-嘿 -关门
- Hey. - Door.
怎么样
How'd it go?
巴伦想要提出动议 公开吉欧根一案的密封文件
Well, Baron wants to sue for the sealed docs in the Geoghan case.
他想要控告教会吗 嘿 那很好啊
He wants to sue the church? Hey, that's great. Yeah.
三年前事发之时 我们报道过吉欧根
We covered Geoghan when the story broke three years ago.
那时巴伦还在迈阿密
Baron was still in Miami.
-其实那时他可能在《时报》 -反正他不在这里
- He might have been at the times then, actually. - He wasn't here.
所以你觉得这有希望吗
So do you think that suit has a chance?
-要看法官了 -以及他属于哪个教区
- Depends on the judge. - And what parish he belongs to.
布莱德利 嗯
Bradlee. Yeah.
好的
Okay.
-巴伦想和我们谈谈 -我们吗
- Baron wants to talk to us. - Us?
-好的 乔 -谢谢
- Okay, Joe. - Thank you.
好的 谢谢
Yes. Okay, thanks.
我已经定了明天要和外部法律顾问见面
I've set up a meeting for tomorrow with outside counsel.
-乔・阿尔巴诺吗 -是的
- Joe albano? - Yeah.
这个案子的法官是谁
Who's the judge in this case?
额
Um...
康斯坦丝・斯威尼
Constance Sweeney.
-难搞的人 -为什么
- Tough. - Why's that?
天主教乖乖女
Good catholic girl. Huh.
所以 从我所读到的来说
So, um, judging from what I've read,
看来我们并没有
it doesn't seem like we've done a
十分彻底地调查过吉欧根的案子
very thorough investigation into the Geoghan case.
-是吗 -并不是
- Is that right? - No, it's not.
我们很认真地调查过这案子
We looked hard at geoghan.
《都市报》的大卫・阿姆斯特朗 还有宗教记者迈克尔・保尔森
David Armstrong from Metro, Michael Paulson for religion.
好吧 但我了解到
Okay, but, uh, just so I understand,
除了我们的日常报道
beyond our daily coverage, we haven't--
我们还没有对劳主教是否知情一事
we haven't committed any long-term investigative resources
展开过任何长期调查
to the question of whether or not cardinal Law knew about this.
是的 没有
No, we haven't.
而这正是你们小组干的事对吗
And that's the kind of thing your team would do?
聚焦吗 嗯 是啊
Spotlight? Well, yeah.
但我们还在调查我和你提过的那个波士顿警局的故事
But we're still prospecting the Boston pd story I told you about.
-你们可以先把那个放一放吗 -可以
- Could you set that aside? - We could.
马蒂 过去聚焦小组总能成功
Marty, in past spotlight's had success in large part
是因为他们自己挑选想调查的项目
because they pick their own projects.
那你们会考虑挑选这个吗
Would you consider picking this one?
我不知道他是不是在写你的事
I don't know if he's writing about you,
但我会告诉他你打过电话
but I will let him know you called.
-好的 拜拜 -嘿
- Okay. Bye. - Hey.
-嘿 怎么样了 -还行吧
- Hey, how'd it go? - Okay.
额 巴伦想我们去弄清楚吉欧根的案子
Uh, Baron wants us to scrub the Geoghan case.
-那很好啊 -我们不是报道过吉欧根吗
- That's great. - Didn't we cover geoghan?
是啊 有个律师声称劳主教知情
Yeah, there's a lawyer alleging cardinal law knew about it.
-嗯 米奇・加拉贝迪安 是吗 -是的
- Mmm. Mitch Garabedian, right? - Yeah.
-我在法院那报道过他 -你能联系到他吗
- I covered him at the courthouse. - Can you get to him?
我只采访过他一次 他还有点个性
I only interviewed him once. He's kind of a character.
-我就喜欢有个性的人 我来搞定他 -很好 你负责
- I like characters. I'll take him. - Good. You take him.
还有 我们要找波特一案中的
Also, we should be talking to the
受害者代表律师谈谈
lawyer who repped the victims in the Porter case.
-埃里克・麦克利什 -那家伙总上电视
- Eric Macleish. - That guy was always on TV.
-波特一案 和我说说 -嗯 额
- The Porter case? Remind me. Yeah, uh--
神父波特 相似的故事
father Porter, similar story.
十年前在福尔里弗猥亵了许多儿童
Molested dozens of kids in Fall River about 10 years ago.
-所以我们要放弃波士顿警局的故事吗 -我赞成
- So we're dropping the Boston pd? - I-I vote yes.
不 我们只是暂时将它放一边
No. We just gotta set it aside for now.
不需要我和你们强调了
I don't need to tell you guys this.
我们这次要比平常更加谨慎
We need to be more discreet than usual.
所有人都会对这件事很感兴趣 不仅仅是《先驱报》
Everybody's going to be interested in this, not just the Herald.
在我们掌握有用的信息之前
We can't let cardinal Law
不能让劳主教知道半点风声
get wind of this till we know what we have.
祝我们好运吧
Good luck with that.
你什么时候走 奶奶
So when do you leave, Nana?
巴士九点会在教会的停车场接我们
The bus is picking us up in the church parking lot at 9:00.
我们有四十个人要去
We have 40 people going.
-多米尼克神父也去吗 -不 他说他运气不好
- And is father Dominic going? - No. He says he's unlucky.
但这和运气没什么关系
But luck has nothing to do with it.
-你知道吗 上次奶奶赢了一百六十刀 -哇噢
- You know, last time Nana won $160. - Wow.
你要告诉她吗
You gonna tell her?
我们还不知道这其中到底有没有料
We don't even know if there's a story yet.
《环球报》控告教会 这本身就是个猛料
Globe sues church? It's gonna be a story.
嘿 丽莎 能把所有相关的剪报都找给我吗
Hey, Lisa. Could you pull all the relevant clips on that for me?
好的
Yeah.
是给聚焦的吗
Is this for spotlight?
准备好了就拿过来吧 谢了
Just drop them off when they're ready. Thanks.
不好意思 你知道出版商的办公室在哪吗
Excuse me. Do you know where the publisher's office is?
好的
Will do.
你好啊 马蒂
How are you, Marty?
还适应吗
Settling in?
嗯 还行
Yeah, I think so.
很好 有什么能为你效劳吗
Good. What can I do for you?
嗯
Um...
我想对吉欧根一案的保护令提出反对
I'd like to challenge the protective order in the Geoghan case.
你想控告天主教会吗
You want to sue the catholic church?
额
Um--
我们现在只是提出动议 不过 是的
we're just filing a motion, but, uh, yes.
你觉得真的有这个必要吗
You think it's that important?
是的
Yes, I do.
因为教会肯定会十分激烈地反击我们
Because obviously the church will fight us very hard on this.
我们的订阅者也会注意到
Which won't go unnoticed by our subscriber base.
其中百分之五十三都是天主教徒
53% of them are catholic.
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
我想他们会感兴趣的
I think they'll be interested.
好吧
Okay.
马蒂 教会的人可能会
Marty, lake street will probably
联系你与主教进行面谈
contact you about a face-to-face with the cardinal.
-这是惯例 -嗯
- It's customary. - Yeah.
他们已经找我了 定在下周
They already have. It's set up for next week.
要是我 我就不会提起这件事
I wouldn't mention this.
有人吗
Hello?
-有什么能帮你的吗 -噢 嗨 我是《波士顿环球报》的麦克・雷赞德斯
- Can I help you? - Oh, hi. I'm Mike Rezendes from the Boston Globe.
我是来见米切尔・加拉贝迪安的
I'm here to see Mitchell Garabedian.
他正在讲电话 先请坐吧
He's on a call. Please have a seat.
好的
Okay.
好了 我在听 继续吧
All right, I'm listening. Go ahead.
好
Okay.
比尔 那些文件死哪去了
Bill! Where the hell are those papers?
我叫你放我桌子上的
I asked you to put 'em on my desk!
大名鼎鼎的沃尔特・罗宾森莅临我的会议室
The famous Walter Robinson in my conference room.
很高兴再会 埃里克 萨夏・法伊弗 埃里克・麦克利什
Good to see you again, Eric. Sacha Pfeiffer, Eric macleish.
-很高兴认识你 -很高兴认识你 你不打高尔夫吧
- Nice to meet you. - Nice to meet you. You don't play golf, do you?
-额 不打 -很好
- Uh, no. - Good.
你这位同事去年
Your colleague here took
在一个慈善活动上敲了我一把
some money off me at a charity event last year.
那一杆真是走运
It was a very lucky putt.
顺便说一句 其实那时我还是闭着眼的
I actually had my eyes closed, by the way.
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
所以有什么可以帮你们的吗
So how can I help you guys?
额 你了解吉欧根那个案子吗
Uh, you're familiar with the geoghan case?
当然 八十个原告
Sure. Eighty plaintiffs.
都是独立的个案
All of them individual cases.
加拉贝迪安都要忙晕了吧
Garabedian must be swimming.
是啊 所有指控都指向劳主教吗
Yeah. And the allegations against cardinal Law?
是啊 挺棘手的
Yeah, it's tricky. Um--
你们要清楚这一点 这些案子都很麻烦
this is what you need to understand. These are shitty cases.
嗯 诉讼时效只有三年
Um, the statute of limitations is only three years,
而大部分受害者
and most of these victims
都要很多年后才来寻求法律的帮助
don't come forward till long after that.
-噢 为什么 -你知道的 他们都是孩子
- Oh. Why is that? - Well, they're kids, you know.
愧疚感 羞耻感
Uh, guilt, shame.
大部分孩子都来自家教严厉的社区
And most of these kids come from tough neighborhoods.
没人想要承认这种事的发生
Nobody wants to admit this kind of thing.
所以在诉讼时效上就已经没辙了
So you're screwed on the time limit.
而且 额 就算给你说通了这一点
And, uh, even if you argue your way around that,
慈善豁免法令的赔偿金就两万美元
the charitable immunity statute caps damages at 20 grand.
猥亵一个儿童才赔偿两万美元
Twenty grand for molesting a child?
是的 这个系统就是这么运转的
That is the way the system is set up, yes.
教会不好对付
The church is tough.
所以最好的方法就是让媒体报道这些案子
So your best shot is to try these cases in the press,
就好像在波特一案中我所做的那样
uh, like I did on Porter.
-嗯 -但大多数受害者
- Mmm. - But you know, most of the victims,
他们都不想和电视媒体扯上关系
they don't want to have anything to do with TV.
还有就是 米奇不算是个好相处的人
And, uh, Mitch isn't exactly a people person.
嗯 而且如果加拉贝迪安
Yeah. And if garabedian
没法说服他的受害者接受媒体的报道
can't get his victims to go before the press,
-那他就真的 -没错
- then he's really-- - Yeah, that's right.
他接下来的路很漫长啊
He has a long road ahead of him.
我的猜测是他并没有抓到劳的把柄
My guess is he doesn't have anything on Law.
什么 你觉得他只是在吓唬他还是
What? You think he's bluffing or--
我觉得他是故意吹嘘来达成更好的交易
I think he's grandstanding to cut a better deal.
看起来有点鲁莽啊
Seems a bit reckless.
你们见过米奇・加拉贝迪安吗
Have you met Mitch Garabedian?
我叫你起草那个动议 比尔
I asked you to write up that motion, Bill.
我没叫你提交
I didn't ask you to file it!
他吗
Mmm?
嘿 比尔
Hey, bill.
嗨
Hi.
-你是谁 -我是《波士顿环球报》的麦克・雷赞德斯
- Who are you? - I'm Mike rezendes from the Boston globe.
我预约了和你一小时前见面的
I had an appointment with you about an hour ago.
我没法和你谈 我很忙 莎伦
I can't talk to you. I'm very busy. Sharon?
她出去买咖啡了 她说她很快回来
She went out for coffee. She said she'd be right back.
我在追踪采访一篇文章
I'm following up on an article.
-《凤凰报》那篇吗 -不是 《环球报》那篇
- The one in the Phoenix? - No. In the globe.
-你读了《凤凰报》那篇吗 -还没有
- Did you see the one in the Phoenix? - No, I didn't.
我觉得写得很好 我这好像有一份
I thought it was very good. I have a copy here somewhere.
没事 我晚点再看
That's all right. I'll track it down.
其实我是在追踪采访
I'm actually following up on a
艾琳・麦克纳马拉专栏里报道的关于你那一个诉讼的
column that Eileen McNamara wrote about your suit.
不是一个 有八十四个
Suits. There are 84 of them.
那不是一起集体诉讼 你要补补背景知识
It's not a class action. You should get your facts straight.
你说得对 我应该了解清楚
No, you're right. I should.
我现在只是想问一些背景信息
So I'm trying to get some background information on--
你没在录音吧
you're not recording this, are you?
没有 我不会不经允许就录音的
Uh, no. I wouldn't do that without asking.
我不能给你看教会的文件
I can't show you the church documents,
如果你想要的是这个的话
if that's what you're after.
-它们是密封的 -嗯 我知道
-They're under seal. -Yeah, I know that.
你知道他们三次试图
Did you know they tried to bring me up
在马塞诸塞州律师监督委员会那告发我吗
before the Massachusetts board of bar overseers three times?
-他们盯我盯得很紧 -教会吗
- They're watching me very closely. - The church?
是的 教会
Yeah. The church. Yeah.
他们想要取消我的律师资格
They'd like to get me disbarred.
事实上 拿开 把那拿开
In fact-- put that away. Put it away.
-没问题 -我不想你记录这段对话
- Sure. - I don't want you recording this
无论什么形式都不行
in any way, shape or form.
笔录 录音 都不行
Not on paper, not on tape, nothing.
事实上 我可能甚至都不应该和你说话 所以
In fact, I probably shouldn't even be speaking to you, so--
听着 加拉贝迪安先生 我知道你有东西不能告诉我
look, Mr. Garabedian, I know there's things you cannot tell me.
但我也知道这当中有个故事
But I also know there's a story here,
而我觉得这是个很重要的故事
and I think it's an important story.
我已经和《凤凰报》谈过了
I already talked to the Phoenix.
我知道 我没读那篇文章也是有原因的
Yeah, and there's a reason I didn't see it.
现在没人看《凤凰报》了
Nobody reads the Phoenix anymore.
它们破产了 它们没什么力量了
They're broke. They don't have any power.
但《环球报》有
The globe does.
如果我们报道这个故事 所有人都会知道
If we cover this story, everybody will hear about it.
教会的力量积攒了无数个世纪 雷赞德斯先生
The church thinks in centuries, Mr. Rezendes.
你觉得你们报纸有这个资源来担当起这件事吗
Do you think your paper has the resources to take that on?
是的 我相信
Yeah, I do.
只要你不介意我问你问题
But if you don't mind me asking, do you?
我现在没空和你聊天 雷赞德斯先生
I can't talk to you right now, Mr. Rezendes.
我真的非常 非常忙
I'm very, very busy.
-莎伦 -谢谢你
- Sharon? - Thank you.
能至少让我和你的一些客户谈一谈吗 那些受害者
Yep. Can I at least talk to some of your clients? The victims?
我真的想这么做
I'd really like to do that.
-明天再给我打电话吧 我要考虑一下 -好的 谢谢你 十分感谢
- Call me tomorrow. I gotta think about it. - Yep. Thank you. Thanks.
-我找到更多剪报了 -放那吧
- I got more clips from the library. - Leave 'em right there.
你们在做关于教会的报道吗
Are you guys doing a story on the church?
不 我们没在做关于教会的报道
No, we are not doing a story on the church.
马特 你有找到这个人的资料吗 菲尔・萨维亚诺
Matt, you find anything on this guy, Phil Saviano?
没有 他是谁
No. Who is he?
他是受害者组织中的成员
He's part of a victims' organization.
波特一案后柯吉恩做过他的报道
Kurkjian did a story on him right after the Porter case.
-还有个受害者组织 -是啊
- There's a victims' organization? - Yeah.
叫作斯纳普 这是
It's called snap. It's, uh,
遭神父虐待之苦的受害者群体的缩写
survivors network of those abused by priests.
-真可怜的名字 -嗯
- Crummy acronym. - Mmm.
-要我查查他吗 -嗯 好的
- You want me to track him down? - Yeah. Bring him in.
你还需要多长时间看完这些剪报
How much longer you need to get through the clips?
好几天吧 有好多
I mean, a few days. There's a lot.
-丽莎还在源源不断地送过来 -行
- Lisa's still sending up more. - Okay.
嘿 大伙 我好像又找到一位神父了
Hey, guys. I think I got another priest.
利亚姆・巴雷特
Liam Barrett.
在费城猥亵过一些孩子
Molested some kids in Philly
后来搬到了波士顿
and was moved to Boston.
故技重施 然后又搬走了
Did the same thing and was moved again.
真的吗 听起来和吉欧根的案子很像
Really? That sounds like geoghan.
-这是我们的剪报吗 -是啊 署名是迪亚哥・日巴迪内亚 1997年
Is that one of our clips? Yeah. Byline's Diego ribadineira, 1997.
肯定是他在做宗教工作之时回来了
Must've been back when he was working religion.
-有后续报道吗 -没多少 只有一小篇
- Was there any folo? - Not much. One short piece.
嗯 教会私下解决了
Huh. The church settled the case.
你不是认识吉姆・苏利文吗
Don't you know Jim Sullivan?
是啊 怎么了
Yeah. Why?
看来教会找他帮忙了
Looks like the church brought him in to help out.
老天 除了曼尼还有人把球打出内场吗
Jesus. Has anybody but Manny gotten the ball out of the infield?
没有 你怎么在弄那个
Nope. Why do you even bother with that thing?
它能让我不去看比赛
It distracts me from the game.
知道还有什么东西能帮到你吗
Know what else is good for that?
噢对 好主意 该我去了
Oh, yeah. Good idea. My round.
-很快回来 有人要吃的吗 -没有
- I'll be right back. Anybody want any food? - No.
-我都有了 -嘿 带根热狗
- I'm all set. - Hey, a hot dog.
-你们有什么进展吗 -当然有
- So, you guys making any progress? - Absolutely.
-那是个好故事 -为什么这么说
- It's a good story. - Why?
因为你也是一个被教会惹怒的叛教者吗
'Cause you're another lapsed catholic pissed off at the church?
-我们找到了很多猛料 -比如说呢
- We've got a lot of good stuff. - Like what?
我只是在专心看比赛 什么都听不到
I'm just watching the game. Omerta?
他们找到另一位神父 利亚姆・巴雷特
They got another priest-- Liam Barrett.
我们报道过他 我只是这么一说 我没说错呀
We reported on him. I'm just saying, we did.
好吧 但这个家伙
Okay, but this guy was shuffled
每过几年就换一个教区
around from parish to parish every few years,
就像吉欧根和波特一样
just like geoghan and Porter.
我觉得这有模式可循
I think there's a pattern.
这推测站不住脚 你还发现了什么
Sounds thin. What else you got?
萨夏从一个受害者组织里
Sacha's got another guy
找到了一个叫菲尔・萨维亚诺的家伙
from a victims' organization-- Phil saviano.
是斯纳普组织里的吗 哦 天呐 我们也报道过他
From snap? Oh, boy. We reported on him too.
你不是在看球赛吗 史蒂夫
I thought you were watching the game, Steve.
-那家伙被伤得很重 -我们写过几篇他的报道
- That guy's pretty banged up. - We did a couple stories on him.
他一直坚持写信
Guy would not stop writing letters.
-他想发起圣战 -怎么 难道问他没什么意义吗
- He wants a holy war. - What, so he's not worth talking to?
-你对加拉贝迪安的调查怎么样了 -还在查呢
- Where are you on garabedian? - I'm working on it.
罗比说麦克利什认为他在虚张声势
Robby says macleish thinks he's bluffing.
本 我觉得这里面有料可挖
I think there's something there, Ben.
给我点可靠的证据 不然你们就别干了
Get me something solid, or I'm taking you off it.
我不想我们因为这件事瞎忙活
I don't want us chasing our tails on this.
不要撞到障碍物
Stay away from that trap!
你想打到那里还早得很呢 伙计
You couldn't reach that trap in a million years, partner.
我以前就打中过
I've reached that trap before.
是么 现在轮到保罗了
Yeah. Now, Paul, maybe.
-怎么样 -挺好的
- How we doing? - We're good.
-我们领先了两分 -很好
- We're two up on the front. - Good.
新编辑怎么样
How's that new editor working out?
呃 他可不怎么喜欢棒球
Well, he doesn't like baseball.
但是 额 他看上去挺聪明的
But, uh, he seems like a smart guy.
嗯 我看过一篇关于他的文章
Yeah, I read an article about him.
上面说他是《环球报》第一位犹太人编辑
Said he's the first Jewish editor of the globe.
真是信息闭塞啊
Must have been a slow news day.
-他结婚了吗 -没有
- He got a family, this guy? - No.
他还没结婚
He is not married.
-是离婚了吗 -我觉得不是
- Divorced? - I don't think so, no.
也就是说这位《环球报》的
So the new editor at the
新编辑是有着犹太信仰的未婚男人
globe is an unmarried man of the Jewish faith
还不喜欢棒球
who hates baseball?
-是啊 -这位子应该给本的
- Yeah. - Should have given it to Ben.
他可是布莱德利家的人
He's a bradlee, for crying out loud.
我想 也许是他手举得还不够快吧
Didn't raise his hand fast enough, I guess.
嘿 顺便一提
Hey, by the way,
我最近在看那个巴雷特神父的资料
I've been reading about this priest, father Barrett.
上面说你参与过这个案子
Said you were involved with that.
巴雷特 哦 坏家伙
Barrett, yeah. Bad egg.
当时教会来找我帮忙 我就参与了
Lake street asked for help. I pitched in.
受害者们说当劳主教
Victim said cardinal law
从费城过来的时候就知道巴雷特的事了
knew about Barrett when he came from Philly.
这是真的吗
Is that true?
你知道我不能谈论这个案子 罗比
You know I can't talk about the case, robby.
呃 私下也不行吗
Well... off the record?
私底下也不行 我不能说
Off the record, I can't talk about it.
-好吧 -这和诉讼有关系吗
- All right. - This related to the lawsuit?
你知道这回事
You know about that?
听着
Look,
我不认识这个叫巴伦的人 也不知道他的计划
I don't know this guy Baron or what his agenda is.
坦白说 我也不在乎
Frankly, I don't care.
我只是不想你替他挡子弹
I just don't want to see you taking a bullet for him.
我觉得你太过火了
I think you're away.
-放在这儿 -我们走 走
- Put it over here. - Let's go. Let's go.
某天我正在上网
So the other day I was on the world wide web.
你想知道的任何事 在网上都找得到
Anything you want to know, it's right there.
我不得不承认 身为一个神父
Now, I have to admit that as a priest,
这不免让我感到有些紧张
this makes me a little nervous.
我该担心自己的工作保障吗
Should I be worried about job security?
我看不需要
I don't think so.
你看 知识是一回事
You see, knowledge is one thing.
但信仰就是另一回事了
But faith-- faith is another.
嘿
Hey.
你不是应该在高尔夫或者别的什么吗
Shouldn't you be golfing or something?
高尔夫可不是个动词
Golfing's not a verb.
我也没有开球时间啊
And I couldn't get a tee time.
人们都是这么称呼的吗 开球时间
Is that what they call it? Tee time?
他们还称它为休闲活动
They also call it a leisure activity.
-你该试试 麦克 -我试了 我去跑步了
- You oughta try it, Mike. - I do. I run.
没错 但你是跑步来上班
Yeah. You run to work.
那你今天在这儿做什么
So why are you here today?
-在反复看萨维亚诺的剪报 -好吧
- Going over these clips of saviano. - Yep.
本和史蒂夫认为这条路走不通
Ben and Steve think it's a dead end.
他们在看比赛时说了一堆废话
They gave me a bunch of crap about it at the game.
嗯 本给我发了邮件
Yeah, Ben e-mailed me.
-是吗 -嗯
- He did? - Yeah.
他说我们该放手了
He said we should let it go.
那你想怎么做
What do you want to do?
我想去查一下萨维亚诺
I want to bring saviano in.
那你不管这些家伙了吗
So, just ignore those guys?
我想我们在这件事上不该理会任何人的话
I think we oughta start ignoring everybody on this one.
这我可以做到
I'm good with that.
那么
Well--
你觉得马蒂对这些有什么看法吗
do you think Marty has any idea what's coming down the pike?
没有 我也觉得他不在乎
Nope. I don't think he cares either.
那可真新鲜
That's refreshing.
嗯
Yeah.
除非他错了
Unless he's wrong.
我一直都很喜欢报刊业
I've always been fascinated with the newspaper business.
我在哈佛读书的时候曾经也和
I used to sit in on the lectures
内曼兄弟一起上过这样的课程
with the neiman fellows when I was at Harvard.
我 额 在文章上看到你曾经也是一个编辑
I, uh-- I read that you were an editor once.
啊 是的
Ah, yes.
嗯 那是很久以前的事了
Yeah, that was a very long time ago.
《密西西比报》
The Mississippi register.
主教管区的小报纸
Small diocesan newspaper.
但对一位三十岁的牧师来说 也是一份重大的责任啊
But for a 30-year-old pastor, it was a big responsibility.
有时过于沉重了
Too much at times.
怎么说
How so?
我曾和埃弗斯兄弟关系不错
I was close with the evers brothers.
我们在公民权利的问题上表明了立场
We took a stand on civil rights.
我们的读者不开心了
Our readership was not pleased.
他们把我当成瞎插手的局外人
They saw me as a meddling outsider.
我能想象
I can imagine.
这位子可不好坐 尤其是在一个小镇子
Tough seat to sit in, especially in a small town.
我想你会发现波士顿其实也是个小地方的 马蒂
I think you'll find that Boston's still a small town too, Marty,
从很多方面看都是
in many ways.
嗯
Hmm.
但如果有任何地方我能帮得上忙的 马蒂 尽管直说
But if I can be of any help, Marty, don't hesitate to ask.
我发现 当一个城市里的各个机构都
I find that the city flourishes
齐心协力的时候 这个城市就能变得繁荣
when its great institutions work together.
谢谢你
Thank you.
就我个人观点来看
Personally I'm of the opinion
一份报纸要能最好地发挥它的功能
that for a paper to best perform its function,
它就不能依靠外在的力量
it really needs to stand alone.
啊 当然了
Ah. Of course.
但我的提议仍然有效
But my offer still stands.
谢谢你
Thank you.
请进
Come in.
哦
Ah.
谢谢 莫林
Thank you, Maureen.
一份小礼物 马蒂
A little gift, Marty.
把它当成是红衣主教对波士顿的指引吧
Think of it as a cardinal's guide to the city of Boston.
我是来见萨夏・法伊弗的
I'm here to see sacha pfeiffer.
-你的名字是 -菲尔・萨维亚诺
- Your name? - Phil saviano.
-好 稍等片刻 -嗯
- Okay, just a minute. - Mm-hmm.
我是第一个跟你们交谈的幸存者吗
So, am I the first survivor you've talked to?
对的 菲尔 你是第一个
Yeah, Phil, you are.
好吧 那么
Okay, well,
首先我要感谢你们今天邀请我来
first of all let me say thank you for having me in today.
其次 我想知道你们是否
And I want you to know that you
和我所属的斯纳普组织全权合作了
have the full cooperation of my organization, snap.
菲尔 你的组织里有多少人
How many members are in your organization, Phil?
上次开会有十一人
We had 11 at our last chapter meeting--
呃 不 是十个 凯伦离开了
uh, no, um, 10. Karen just moved.
-你们团队里还有个女人 -当然了
- You had a woman in your group? - Of course.
他们不会区别对待的 施虐不分男女
They don't discriminate, not when it comes to abuse.
这和是不是同性恋也没关系
And this has nothing to do with being gay.
这就是神父利用职权来强奸孩子
What this is is priests using the collar to rape kids.
都是孩子啊 有男有女
Kids. Boys and girls.
那时我十一岁
I was 11,
我被伍斯特市的大卫・霍利神父折磨
and I was preyed upon by father David holley in worcester.
我不是说向他祷告 而是受他折磨
And I don't mean prayed for. I mean preyed upon.
-你们中有谁是天主教徒吗 -我在信奉天主教的家庭里长大
- Are any of you catholic? - I was raised catholic.
不过现在我去我妻子的基督教长老会
Now I go to my wife's presbyterian church.
我没有信仰
I'm lapsed.
但我有时和奶奶一起去教堂
I go to church with my grandmother sometimes.
之前说我们都在信奉天主教的家庭长大是一件很光荣的事 但现在
It's safe to say we were all raised catholic, but now--
-没这种感觉了 -好吧
- not so much. - Okay.
那么 我告诉你们
Well, let me tell you,
如果你是一个出身贫寒的穷小子
when you're a poor kid from a poor family,
宗教就很重要了
religion counts for a lot.
而且若是神父能注意到你 那可是非同小可的大事
And when a priest pays attention to you, it's a big deal.
他会让你收集赞美诗
He asks you to collect the
或者倒垃圾 你会觉得自己是特别的
hymnals or take out the trash, you feel special.
就像上帝让你帮忙一样
It's like god asking for help.
所以当他给你讲黄段子的时候 你可能会觉得有点奇怪
So maybe it's a little weird when he tells you a dirty joke.
但你们有了共同的秘密 于是你选择了顺从
But now you got a secret together, so you go along.
然后他给你看色情杂志 你也顺从他
Then he shows you a porno mag, and you go along.
就这样 你一直顺从他 听他的话
And you go along, and you go along,
直到某天他让你为他打手枪或吹喇叭
until one day he asks you to jerk him off or give him a blow job.
你也会顺从他 因为你觉得非做不可
And so you go along with that too because you feel trapped,
因为他一手栽培了你
because he has groomed you.
你怎么能对上帝说不呢 对吧
How do you say no to god, right?
你们要理解
See, it is important to
这不仅仅是身体上的虐待
understand that this is not just physical abuse.
这也是精神上的虐待
It's spiritual abuse too.
当一个神父对你做了这些事 他抢劫了你的信仰
And when a priest does this to you, he robs you of your faith.
所以你要么酗酒 要么嗑药
So you reach for the bottle or the needle,
而这些都不起作用时 你就只能纵身跳桥
or if those don't work, you jump off a bridge.
这就是我们称自己为幸存者的原因
That's why we call ourselves survivors.
你们读过詹森・内里的书吗
Have you read Jason Berry's book?
他写了路易斯安那的高瑟案
He wrote about the gauthe case in Louisiana.
-怎么写 -g-a-u-t-h-e
- That's g-- - g-a-u-t-h-e.
来 去和理查德・赛普谈谈吧
Here. And talk to Richard sipe.
他在教会的其中一间治疗中心工作
He worked in one of the church's treatment centers.
他以前是神父 娶了一位修女
He's an ex-priest. Married a nun.
这给你 这是科斯案的证词
Here. This is his testimony from the kos case.
菲尔 治疗中心是什么
Phil, what's a treatment center?
就是当神父被抓到时会被送去的地方
It's where they send priests when they get caught.
我知道的都在这盒子里了
This is all here in the box.
我五年前就寄给你们了
I sent this to you guys five years ago.
呃 寄给《环球报》吗 你寄给谁了
Uh, to the globe? Who did you send it to?
我不想说是谁 但他们表示不感兴趣
I don't wanna say who, but they said they weren't interested.
但我们确实做过几篇关于你的报道 我在剪报里看到了
But we did run a couple stories on you. I saw them in the clips.
嗯 可坦白说 那根本不够
Yeah, but to be completely frank, it wasn't enough.
你们要明白
You guys gotta understand.
这事关重大
This is big.
这不仅关乎波士顿
This is not just Boston.
它关乎整个国家 整个世界
It's the whole country. It's the whole world.
它的矛头直指梵蒂冈
And it goes right up to the Vatican.
你有证据吗 菲尔
Do you have any proof of that, Phil?
不 还没 但想想吧 他们数量这么多
No. Not yet. But there are so many of them.
不然他们干嘛要极力隐瞒这么久
How else could they have hidden it for so long?
-什么数量那么多 -神父啊
- So many what? - Priests!
神父
Priests!
我知道仅波士顿就有十三个
I know of 13 right here in Boston.
你知道波士顿有十三个神父对儿童进行性骚扰吗
You know 13 priests in Boston who have molested children?
是啊 你为什么要重复我说的每句话
Yeah! Why do you keep repeating everything I say?
我只是想确认清楚
I just like to clarify things.
早在五年前我寄给你们这些东西的时候
Maybe you should have clarified
你们就该搞清楚了
it five years ago when I sent you all of this stuff.
都在这里面了
It's all right here.
能借用一下洗手间吗
May I use your bathroom?
嗯 好啊 菲尔 走吧
Yeah, sure, Phil. Come on.
你们怎么看
Well, what do you think?
嗯 这家伙有备而来 这点毫无疑问
Well, the guy's got an agenda, that's for sure.
-你这么认为吗 -他明显经历了很多
- You think? - He's obviously been through a lot.
但他很聪明 而且如果他关于十三个神父的话是对的
But he's smart, and if he's right about 13 priests--
嗯 但我们很难相信这个家伙
yeah, it might be a big "If" With this guy.
调查一下他的背景
Do a background check on him.
追查一下他组织里其它幸存者的情况
And follow up with some of the other survivors of his group.
我去找这位前神父 赛普
I'll track down this ex-priest, sipe.
好 但也要盯紧加拉贝迪安 那个更重要
Okay, but stay on garabedian. That's more important.
啊 加拉贝迪安 真是烦人
Ah. Garabedian. What a pain in the ass.
你也可以很烦人 麦克
You can be a pain in the ass, Mike.
嗯
Mmm.
米切尔 真巧啊 你还好吗
Mitchell, what a surprise. How are you?
-我很好 雷赞德斯先生 -那就好
- I'm fine, Mr. Rezendes. - Good.
我还没收到你的回电 我给你留了好多言
I haven't heard back from you. I left you a couple of messages.
我特别忙 没什么时间听电话
I've been very busy. I-I don't have time for calls.
我想也是 听着 听着 米奇
I'm sure you don't. Listen, listen, Mitch.
让我和几位受害者谈谈吧
Let me talk to a couple of the victims.
采访时你可以旁听
You could sit in on the interview.
你要不满意 随时可以结束采访
If you're not happy, you could kill it.
我和我的客户谈过了
I spoke to my clients.
他们不想上报 抱歉
They don't want to be in the press. I'm sorry.
我能理解 但我不会用真名的
I get that, but I don't need to name names.
-我不信任你 雷赞德斯先生 -我知道你不信我
- I don't believe you, Mr. Rezendes. - I'm sure you don't.
-听着 米切尔 -不 雷赞德斯先生 拜托
- Listen, Mitchell. - Look, Mr. Rezendes, please--
我不是来给他们写个人档案的 我在做更重要的事
I'm not writing a profile here. I'm working on something bigger.
更重要 我不懂这是什么意思
Bigger? I don't know what that means.
我不该告诉你这些
I'm not supposed to tell you this,
但我这些调查是为聚焦小组做的
but I'm digging around for spotlight.
-聚焦在关注这事 -嗯 我们正在调查
- Spotlight's on this? - Yeah, we're looking into it.
但你得帮我 你得让我
But you gotta help me. You gotta
和那些受害者们谈谈 拜托
let me talk to some of these victims. Please.
拜托了
Please.
明早九点半再来吧
Come back tomorrow, 9:30 am.
谢谢
Thank you.
-法伊弗小姐 -乔
- Ms. Pfeiffer? - Joe?
哦 见鬼
Oh, shoot!
-没事没事 -抱歉 请坐
- That's okay. - Sorry. Please sit.
谢谢
Thank you.
-这位置可以吗 -很好呀
- Is this table okay? - This is perfect.
我等您的时候吃了一块松饼
I had a muffin while I was waiting.
其实是两块 我一紧张就吃东西
Two, actually. I eat when I'm nervous.
其实我也是诶
I do that too, actually.
希望我没迟到 菲尔告诉我是一点
I hope I'm not late. Phil told me 1:00.
不 你没迟到 是我来早了
No, you're fine. I got here early.
早了差不多一个小时
About an hour.
呃 你介意我做些笔记吗 可以吗
Um, would you mind if I took some notes? Would that be all right?
你不介意我做点笔记吧
You don't mind if I take some notes, do you?
-你会写我的名字吗 -不会
- Are you gonna use my name? - No.
如果你不想我写 我就不写
Not if you don't want me to, no.
我刚有了个孩子
I just had a kid.
他才一岁 但我不确定我是否想让他知道这事
He's only one, but I'm not sure I want him to know about this.
嗯 我理解
Sure. I get that.
帕特里克 你随时都可以结束这个采访 好吗
You can stop this interview at any time, Patrick. All right?
好的
Okay. All right.
你可以记笔记
Go ahead with your notes.
好的 那么
Okay. So, um--
第一次事发时你们住在哪里
where'd you live when it first happened?
在海德公园另一边的楼里
In the projects, over in Hyde park.
是在超市那边吗
Over by the stop & shop?
嗯 你知道呀
Yeah. You know it?
嗯 我当过几年出租车司机
Yeah, I drove a cab for a few years.
那里很早开门 咖啡也难喝 对吧
Open early. Bad coffee, right?
嗯 大概吧
Yeah. I guess.
那时你几岁
How old were you when it happened?
十二岁
I was 12.
就在我父亲自杀后发生的
Just after my dad killed himself.
哦 天呐
Oh, geez.
他是个十足的人渣
He was a real piece of shit.
我母亲 也不是很稳定
And my mom, she wasn't so stable either.
-什么意思 -我是说她疯了
- How do you mean? - I mean she was nuts.
她有精神分裂症
She was a schizophrenic.
都一样不是好人
Same shit.
你第一次遇到吉欧根是什么时候
When did you first meet geoghan?
我姐姐 在邓金甜甜圈店里看到他
Well, my sister, she saw him over in the dunkin' donuts.
告诉他父亲去世了 他马上赶了过来
Tells him about my old man passing, and he rushed right over.
那个修女 芭芭拉
This nun, sister Barbara,
负责一个组织 专门接收问题家庭来的孩子
ran this group for kids from troubled families.
嗯 那个组织在哪里
Mm-hmm. Where was that?
额 在多尔切斯特的圣安布罗斯
Uh, St. Ambrose in Dorchester.
好的
Okay.
就是她把我介绍给尚利神父的
She's the one who introduced me to father shanley.
他是街区的神父
He was a street priest.
留长发 很时髦
Long hair. Very hip.
他邀我去他后湾区[波士顿上层社会住宅区]的公寓
He invited me to his apartment in back bay.
-后湾区哪里 -灯塔街
- Where in back bay? - Beacon street.
-灯塔 好的 -你是本地人吗
- Beacon. Okay. - Are you from here?
额 不是的 我在俄亥俄州长大 但我母亲是南方人
Uh, no. I grew up in Ohio, but my mom's from southie.
好吧 所以你懂的 我之前从没见过后湾区
All right, so you get it. I'd never even seen back bay.
那第一次见面后发生了什么呢 乔
So what happened on that first visit, Joe?
呃 一开始他很好 很有趣 也很随意
Well, he was very nice at first, very funny, very casual.
我觉得他看得出来我是同性恋
And I think he could tell I was gay,
他让我看了他的手机 趴在婴儿床上看的
so he showed me this mobile he had, like over a baby's crib.
-嗯 -但是给我看了很多不同的东西
- Mm-hmm. - But with different words.
什么同性恋 跨性别 还有双性恋
"Homosexual." "Transsexual." "Bisexual."
嗯 你那时知道自己是同性恋吗 乔
Okay. And did you know you were gay at that time, Joe?
知道
Yeah.
但我没有告诉任何人
But that wasn't information
在多尔切斯特没人知道
I was sharing with anybody. Not in Dorchester.
嗯
Okay.
他让你看了手机之后呢
So, what happened after he showed you the mobile?
呃 我有点被吓到了
Well, I was a little freaked out.
我想他看出来了
I think he could tell.
于是他说 你知道吗 我们来玩脱衣扑克会好一点哦
So he said, you know, what'll help is if we play strip poker.
毫无疑问我输了
Of course I lost.
然后 额 事情就发生了
And, uh, things went on from there.
你能给我讲讲细节吗
Can you tell me specifically what happened?
细节就是 他
Specifically, he--
他对我性骚扰
he molested me.
乔 我想这时候我们要很注意用语
Joe, I think that the language is gonna be so important here.
我们不能美化这件事 只说“性骚扰”是不够的
We can't sanitize this. Just saying "Molest" Isn't enough.
人们得知道究竟发生了什么
People need to know what actually happened.
-我们应该把这些打包带走 -是的
- We should probably get these to go. - Right.
吉欧根来了 我母亲 你知道 她
Geoghan shows up, and my mom, you know, she's--
她很激动
she's thrilled.
我是说 就像看到上帝似的 你懂吧
I mean, this was like god showing up, you know?
嗯 之后发生什么了呢
Sure. Right. So what happened then?
你真的要听这些破事吗
You really want to hear this shit?
对 帕特里克 我要听
Yeah. Yeah, Patrick, I do.
他说带我去吃冰激凌
He offers to take me to get ice cream.
你知道的 他是神父 我是小孩 所以我就去了
You know, he's a priest, I'm a kid, so I go.
嗯
Sure.
然后我们开车回家
So we're driving home and he--
他开始轻拍我的腿
he starts patting my leg and--
然后
you know, then...
他的手就滑过来了
His hand just slides right up and he--
然后抓住我的性器
he grabs my dick.
你知道吗 我都呆住了
You know, I-- I just froze up.
我完全吓呆了 动弹不得
I was fucking petrified. I-I couldn't move.
我不知道怎么办 那时我还是个孩子
I didn't know what to do. I was just a little kid.
嗯
Yeah.
你知道 我压根都没吃到冰激凌
You know, I never even touched my ice cream.
它就在我手里融化了
It just melted down my arm.
那你 额
Did you, um--
那以后你还有见他吗
did you see him again after that?
嗯
Yeah.
好了 可以了 这次就先说这么多吧
All right. That's good. Let's stop there for now.
好
Sure.
他说这样做能让我更适应自己的身体
He said it was a way to make me more comfortable with my body.
嗯 那这之后呢
Mmm. So what happened after that?
嗯 他脱下自己的衣服说
Well, he took off his clothes and he said,
“我一直以来都很压抑
"I've been so depressed,
但也许你能让我开心点 帮我吹喇叭”
but maybe you can cheer me up and give me a blow job."
真是谦谦君子
Classy guy.
-那你照做了吗 -我做了
- And did you? - Yeah.
我想你肯定在想
I know you must be thinking,
为什么我会为一个比我
why would I ever do that to
大三十岁的奇葩做这种事
some creepy guy who's 30 years older than me?
但你要明白
But what you have to understand
这是我人生中第一次
is that this is the first time in my life
有人告诉我同性恋并没有什么错
that someone told me that it was okay to be gay.
-而且他还是一个神父 -嗯
- And it was a priest. - Right.
所以你为他口交了
So you had oral sex.
你们有过性行为吗
Did you have intercourse?
有
Yes.
不是当时 是后来
Not then, but later.
那让我痛苦了很久
It really messed me up.
我现在清醒了 但那 那就是一切的开始
I'm sober now, but that-- that was the beginning of it all.
那让我十分困惑 你懂吧
It's very confusing, you know,
通过这种方式了解性是什么
to be introduced to sex like that and then--
然后喜欢上男人 实在是
and then to be attracted to men, it's--
抱歉 我就知道我会忍不住的
I'm sorry. I knew I was gonna do this.
-哦 抱歉 -没关系
- Oh, I'm sorry. - Don't be sorry.
没事了 乔 没事了
It's okay, Joe. It's okay.
那里是有一个教堂
Of course there is a church right there.
还有一个操场
And a playground.
乔 你有试过和谁讲这些吗
Joe, did you ever try and tell anyone?
和谁讲呢 神父吗
Like who? A priest?
能用一下你的电话吗
Can I use your phone?
好的 你知道放在哪儿
Yeah, sure. You know where it is.
如果你想的话可以写我的名字
You can use my name if you want.
谢谢 帕特里克
Thanks, Patrick.
不要谢我 把那些混蛋抓住 好吗
Don't thank me. Just get these assholes, will you?
他是其中的幸运儿
He's one of the lucky ones.
至少他还活着
He's still alive.
-要来杯茶吗 萨夏 -不了 奶奶 谢谢
- Do you want a cup of tea, sacha? - I'm okay, Nana. Thanks.
-你好 -嗨 乔 我是萨夏・法伊弗
- Hello? - Hi, Joe. It's sacha pfeiffer.
-嗨 萨夏 你好吗 -很好 谢谢
- Hi, sacha. How are you? - I'm good, thanks.
呃 听着 乔 我只想再问一件事
Um, listen, Joe, I just wanted to follow up on one thing.
你向菲尔・萨维亚诺说过这些 是吗
You talked to Phil saviano about all of this, right?
嗯 是的 我去过几次斯纳普的会议
Yeah, I did. I went to a couple of snap meetings.
菲尔有没有建议你采取一些措施呢
And did Phil ever suggest you do anything about it?
没有 会议也不是关于这些的
No. The meetings weren't really about that.
其中一些人找了律师
A couple of them had gone to a lawyer,
但我觉得不值得
but I didn't think it was worth it.
为什么
Why not?
去那里要填很多表 太耗费时间精力了
There were just so many forms to fill out. It was overwhelming.
他说最多也只能为我争取到一点赔偿 所以
And he said he could only get me a small settlement, so--
-谁说的 -那个律师说的
- wh-who said that? - The lawyer told me that.
所以你是有去见过律师
So you did go and see a lawyer?
嗯 但最后还是没有用
Yeah, but I didn't end up using him,
所以我想这个也不重要吧
so I didn't think it was important.
抱歉 我没有要隐瞒的意思
I'm sorry. I'm not trying to hide anything.
不 我知道的 乔
No, I-I-I know, Joe.
你还记得那个律师的名字吗
Do you remember his name? The lawyer?
不 但菲尔可能会知道
No. But maybe Phil would know.
他在波特案时经常出镜 长得也很帅
The guy was on TV a lot during the Porter case. He was handsome.
是埃里克・麦克利什吗
Was it Eric macleish?
嗯 就是他 麦克利什
Yeah, that's it. Macleish.
我觉得他很帅
I thought he was very handsome.
-嗨 -嗨
- Hey. - Hey.
我刚刚在新闻编辑室
I was just in the newsroom.
斯威尼法官确定了听证会的日期
Judge sweeney set a date for the hearing.
-真的吗 什么时候 -两周后
- Really? When? - Two weeks.
-在斯普林菲尔德 -哦
- In Springfield. - Oh.
卡内洛斯凯开始坐庄收注了 一注十块
Canellos started a pool. Ten bucks to get in.
有人买《环球报》赢吗
Anyone picking the globe?
他坐的庄是斯威尼要用多久来否决我们
He's only taking bets on how fast sweeney rules against us.
罗比
Robby.
-收到我的留言了吗 -收到了
- Did you get my message? - I did.
看样子尚利神父就是我们的第四位了
Looks like father shanley could be our fourth priest.
嗯 我想是的
Yeah, I think he is.
-你追查麦克利什了吗 -我刚刚和菲尔谈过了
- Did you follow up with macleish? - I just talked to Phil.
他说麦克利什处理了很多这种案子
He said macleish dealt with a number of these cases.
-看来他忘记说了 -嗯
- Guess he forgot to mention that. - Yeah.
明天我要去法庭
I'm gonna go to the courthouse tomorrow,
看看能不能找到他经手的起诉教会的案子
see if I can find any cases he settled against the church.
好的 找到了给我电话 晚安
All right. Call me after you do. Good night.
好的 晚安
Okay. Good night.
嗨
Hey.
-你想 谈谈吗 -嗯
- You wanted to, uh, chat? - Yeah.
-我吃晚饭要迟到了 不如送我一下吧 -好的
- I'm late for a dinner. Wanna walk me out? - Sure.
-天呐 这些人都不回家的吗 -显然不
- Geez. Does that guy ever go home? - Apparently not.
还有些人不坐穿编辑室的椅子
I got guys who won't leave till he does.
是绝对不会离开的
He's wearing out the goddamn newsroom.
-吉欧根案的进展如何 -正在追查更多的受害者
- Where are we on geoghan? - Following up on more victims.
-我想扩大调查范围 -为什么
- I want to expand the investigation. - Why?
我们已经找到四个神父了 说不准真的有十三个
We got a fourth priest. There might be as many as 13.
-十三个 -是啊
- Thirteen? - Yeah.
-你的料从哪来的 -菲尔・萨维亚诺
- Who's your source? - Phil saviano.
老天啊 罗比 我告诉过
Jesus Christ, robby. I told
-麦克那家伙可是 -我知道 我知道
- Mike that guy's a fuckin'-- - I know, I know.
我觉得萨维亚诺可能是可信的 本
I think saviano might be legit, Ben.
想给我解释一下吗
Want to elaborate on that?
不 还不行
No. Not really.
只是觉得事情仿佛越发复杂了 我的直觉
It just feels like this thing's stacking up. That's my gut.
-好吧 -好的
- Okay. - Okay. Good.
谢谢
Thank you.
你好
Hello?
雷赞德斯先生
Mr. Rezendes?
呃 我是 你是哪位
Uh, yeah. Who's this?
我是理查德・赛普
It's Richard sipe
噢 嗨 理查德 你还好吗
Oh, yeah. Hey, Richard. How are you?
-我很好 -额 谢谢你打电话过来
- I'm good. - Uh, thanks for calling.
额 菲尔・萨维亚诺给了我你的名字
Look, uh, Phil saviano g-gave me your name.
我在想能不能问你几个问题
I was wondering if I could ask you a few questions.
-当然可以 -好极了
- Of course. Yeah. - Great.
菲尔说你以前在一个巴尔的摩的
Uh, so Phil told me that you were working
一个教会治疗中心工作
a-at one of the church's treatment centers in Baltimore.
是的 西顿精神科研究所
Yes. The seton psychiatric institute.
由仁爱修女会运营
It was run by the daughters of charity.
那是什么时候 理查德
And, uh, when was that, Richard?
我1965年加入了这个研究所
Well, I started my psychotherapy fellowship there in 1965,
-恩 -我在那里呆了五年
- okay. - And I was there for five years,
但接下来我花了三十年
but I spent the next 30
研究性侵别人的神父和那些受害者
studying abusive priests and their victims.
-真的吗 -恩
- Really? - Mm-hmm.
所以你一直关注的就只有这个吗
And that's-- that's been your sole focus?
听着 麦克 教会想让
Look, Mike, the church wants
大家觉得里面只有几只害群之马
us to believe that it's just a few bad apples.
但这只是冰山一角
But it's a much bigger problem than that.
问题有多严重 理查德
How much bigger, Richard?
根据我的调查
Well, based on the research,
我将它归为一种可识别的精神现象
I would classify it as a recognizable psychiatric phenomenon.
可真是大问题啊
That's big.
-嘿 麦可 -嘿
- Hey, Mac. - Hey.
如果我想要一个神父的历史资料
If I wanted historical data on a priest,
想知道他所分配的教区
parishes he's been assigned to,
我在哪里可以找到这些资料
where would I find that?
吉欧根那件案子吗 都在那些剪报里
The geoghan case? It's all in the clips.
丽莎有资料
Lisa has the source material.
如果是另一个神父呢
What if it was for another priest,
没有上过报纸的
one that hadn't been in the papers?
你在找另一个神父 谁啊
You're looking at another priest? Who you looking at?
有办法吗
Any ideas?
拜托 马特 你不打算告诉我吗
Come on, Matt. You're not gonna tell me?
我要去开会了 谢谢你 麦可 你好啊 史蒂夫
I gotta get to a meeting. Thanks, Mac. Hey, Steve.
总教区出版了年度名录
The archdiocese puts out an annual directory,
每个神父和教区都有记录
every priest and parish.
好极了
That's great.
有98年以前的吗
Do these go back any further than '98?
恩 一直到八十年代
Oh, yeah. Going back to the '80s in the mez.
更早以前的话 你得去波士顿公共图书馆了
Beyond that, you gotta go to bpl.
-谢了 丽莎 -不客气
- The mez, huh? Thanks, Lisa. - You bet.
他说他们的目标是同一种孩子
He said they all target the same kind of kid.
家庭收入低 没有父亲 家庭支离破碎
Low-income families, absentee fathers, broken homes.
因此吉欧根这种人
So a guy like geoghan
找上这些男孩不是因为他偏爱他们
goes after boys not because he prefers them,
而是因为这些男孩更懂羞耻 不喜欢说话
but because they have more shame, less likely to talk.
恩
Hmm.
-这些人就是禽兽 罗比 -嗯
- These guys are predators, robby. - Yeah.
我和赛普谈过了
I-I-I talked to sipe.
他说在六十年代的西顿研究所见过许多这样的神父
He said he's seen dozens of them in the '60s in seton.
他称之为一种“现象”
He called it a "Phenomenon."
-他为什么没有揭示于众 -他有
- Why didn't he go public? - He did.
但教会竭力败坏了他的名声
But the church made a huge effort to discredit him.
恶意宣传 有威望的主教还发表公开声明
Smear campaigns, public statements by prominent bishops.
就像萨维亚诺和加拉贝迪安说的一样
It's just like saviano said. And garabedian.
-你有什么进展吗 -找到更多的受害者
- You getting anywhere with him? - More victims.
更多的受害者 你没有问到底吗
More victims. You can't empty his pockets?
我会尽力的 但是要更多时间
I'll get to him. I just need more time.
拜托了 麦克 你得搞定他
Come on, Mike. You gotta get him.
我会的 我会的
I'll get him. I'll get him.
天呐 这是什么怪味
Jesus. What the hell is that smell?
角落里有一只死老鼠
There's a dead rat in the corner.
-你找到了什么 -教会的名录
- What have you got? - Church directories.
上面有马萨诸塞州每个神父的名字
It's every priest in Massachusetts,
还有他们所在的教区
what parish they're assigned to.
-是官方资料吗 -恩 我觉得可以在里面
- Are these official? - Yeah. I figured it could help us track down
找到一些萨维亚诺提到过的神父
some of the priests saviano mentioned,
也许能找到更多的受害者
maybe find some more victims.
-能开点灯吗 -我找不到开关
- Can we turn on some more lights? - I couldn't find the switch.
-你要我的眼镜吗 -不 不用
- You wanna borrow my glasses? - No, I'm good. I'm good.
看 1983年
Look. 1983.
约翰・吉欧根 多切斯特圣布兰登街教区
John geoghan, St. Brendan's parish, Dorchester.
我们可以找到任何一年的任何神父吗
So we can find out where any priest is in any given year?
恩 我找到了
Yeah, I got him here at--
-哈 -什么
- huh. - What?
1980年 吉欧根从教区离职
1980. The year geoghan was pulled from jp.
上面说他在休病假
It says he's on sick leave.
不会吧 真的吗
Come on. It really says that?
1991年的在哪里
Where is, uh, 1991?
这里
Yeah. Here ya go.
我看看利亚姆・巴雷特
Let me see this. Barrett. Barrett. Liam.
我看不清 帮我找找利亚姆・巴雷特
I can't read that. Look for a Liam Barrett in there.
1991年他从查尔斯顿离职
1991's the year they pulled him out of charlestown.
“利亚姆・巴雷特”
"Barrett, Liam."
-恩 -“休病假”
- Yeah. - "Sick leave."
这是官方说法
It's an official designation.
把这些拿到楼上
Let's get these upstairs.
马特 你查查看萨维亚诺告诉我们的神父
Matt, check on those priests saviano gave us.
-我是罗比 -我在法庭
- Robby. - I'm down at the courthouse.
有点不对劲
Something's not right here.
-尚利的也没有 萨夏 -好的 谢谢
- Nothing on shanley either, sacha. - Okay, thanks.
-我们得再找麦克利什谈话 -真的吗 为什么
- Um, we need to talk to macleish again. -Really. Why?
这里什么也没有 任何记录都没有
Huh? There's nothing here. There aren't any records.
多谢等待 抱歉伙计们 我一直在接电话
Thanks for waiting. So sorry, guys. Stuck on a call.
-没事 你怎么样 -很好
- Not a problem. How are you? - Good.
-谢谢和我们会面 -应该的 什么事
- Thanks for meeting us. - You bet. What's up, guys?
麦克利什先生 你认识一个叫保罗・尚利的神父吗
Mr. Macleish, are you familiar with a priest named Paul shanley?
恩 我认识
Yes, I am familiar with him.
你有处理过尚利神父的案子吗
And have you settled cases against father shanley?
你们能理解的 我不能告诉你们
As I'm sure you can understand, I can't discuss that with you.
恩 那罗纳德・帕奎因神父呢
Yeah, h-how about, uh, father Ronald paquin?
我也不能告诉你们 拜托了
Well, I can't discuss that with you either. Come on, guys.
我们知道你帮他们处理过几场官司
We understand you've settled several cases against each of them.
即使我是有参与这些官司
Even if I'd been involved in those cases,
调解结果也是保密的
the settlements would be confidential
如果我说出来的话 会被取消律师资格
and I could be disbarred for acknowledging their existence.
-好吗 -恩
- Okay? - Mm-hmm.
听着 我说过这些案子很棘手
Look, I told you guys these are tough cases.
大多数人只想他们承认
Most of these folks, they just want some acknowledgment
发生了什么事情
of what happened.
让他们和主教坐下来 拿点钞票
We got 'em a sit-down with the bishop and a little dough,
这是最好的结果了
and that's the best they could hope for.
当然了 这是神父所期待的最好结果
Well, it's certainly the best the priests could hope for.
不 教会保证了
No, the church promised
他们会开除这些神父
they'd take the priests out of circulation.
你有后续跟进吗
And did you follow up on that?
你们还有什么事吗
Do you guys need anything else?
有 为什么没有任何记录
Yes. Why aren't there any records?
我之前在法庭
I was down at the courthouse earlier.
那里没有任何关于这些调解结果的记录
There aren't any records of any of these settlements.
我们直接和教会沟通的
We dealt directly with the church.
我们起草一份交款通知书 送到了主教办公室
We would draw up a demand letter and send it to the chancery.
-你没在法院上提交过任何文件吗 -这是私人调解
- You never filed anything in court? - It's a private mediation.
那么 这只是
So, this is just you
你和总教区的律师在操作吗
and the archdiocese's lawyers in a room?
-是的 -还有其他人吗
- Correct. - Anyone else?
有时候教会会请
Occasionally the church would
其他辩护律师来帮忙
bring in another defense attorney to help out.
你知道他们的名字吗
You have names?
不 我不知道
Nope. No, I don't.
那这一切都是私下操纵咯
So this was all under the table?
根本没有文件可循
There's no paper trail at all.
为了达成私下和解
The victim has to sign a
受害者不得不签保密协议
confidentiality agreement to get the settlement.
律师作为第三方 然后教会隐瞒真相
The lawyer takes a third, and the church sweeps it under the rug.
-这完全是非法的啊 -事情还要更复杂
- It's a freakin' racket. - It's more complicated than that.
麦克利什有责任
Macleish has got a duty
让客户得到最好的结果
to the client to get the best deal he can.
当然 但他们要代表多少受害者
Sure. But how many victims do you
从中获取多少利益才能出手帮忙
represent and profit from before you say something?
加拉贝迪安会说一个也没有
Garabedian would say none.
这就是为什么他要把这些案子送上法庭
That's why he's taking these cases to court.
-他想要人们知道这件事 -我同意
- He wants people to know about this. - I agree.
本 先把法律道德放一边
And legal ethics aside, Ben,
像麦克利什这样的处理方式
I mean, operating the way macleish has
只会让这些侵害案件不为人知
all but guarantees that the abuse stays under wraps.
恩 麦克利什确认了萨维亚诺说的那些神父吗
Yeah. Did macleish confirm all saviano's priests?
没有 他受到了保密协议的限制
No. He's limited by his confidentiality agreement.
但他显然调解了很多神父的案子
But clearly he's settled cases against a number of them.
菲尔让我联系到了一些其他受害者
Phil's put me in touch with some of the other victims.
我相信能找到所有神父
I'm pretty confident all of his priests are gonna check out.
所以是有十三个神父吗
So it is 13 priests?
-恩 -看起来是这样
- Yeah. - Looks that way.
天呐
Holy shit.
好的 继续努力
Okay. Keep going.
抱歉 你叫什么
I'm sorry. What was the name again?
额 巴伦
Uh, baron.
B-a-r-o-n
B-a-r-o-n.
我没找到 等一会儿
I'm having trouble finding it. Just give me a second.
没事了 金姆 我为他担保
It's okay, Kim. I can vouch for him.
我是皮特・康利 天主教慈善会的董事
I'm Pete conley. I'm on the board of catholic charities.
欢迎来到波士顿 巴伦先生
Welcome to Boston, Mr. Baron.
-谢谢 -感谢你加入我们
- Thank you. - I appreciate you joining us.
我们对在波士顿所做的工作感到很自豪
We're very proud of the work we do here in Boston.
主教说你之前跟他见过面 聊得挺愉快的
Oh, the cardinal said you had a nice visit.
是的 没错
Yes, we did.
他是个很了不起的人 很高兴你们有机会能一起谈话
He's an extraordinary man. I'm glad you had a chance to chat.
玩得开心吗
Enjoying yourself?
老实说 我不太擅长参加这些活动
Uh, to be honest, these events aren't really my strong suit.
-恩 -你参加了慈善会吗
- Yeah. - Are you involved with the charity?
没有 我有些朋友参加了
Not directly, no. Several of my friends are.
我们都读的波士顿天主教高中
We all went to high school at bc high.
就在《环球报》的对面
That's the school across the street from the globe.
-很容易看到嘛 -恩
- It's hard to miss. - Yeah.
而且逃课还很容易被抓到
Hard to get away from too, apparently.
如果你想见红衣主教的话
The, uh, cardinal's in the corner,
他就在那边
if you're so inclined.
-我们见过了 -真的吗
- We've met. - Really?
他有提到起诉吗
Did he mention the suit?
没有 但他给了我一本《教义问答书》
No, but he did give me a copy of the catechism.
好吧
Yeah.
他的精明并不是众人皆知的
Well, the cardinal's not known for his subtlety.
在调查波特的时候
During the Porter investigation,
他真的借用了神的力量对《环球报》进行压制
he literally called down the power of god on the globe.
此话怎讲
How'd that play out?
一周后 我们的编辑在滑雪时摔断了腿
A week later, our editor broke his leg skiing.
要鲜虾吐司吗 先生们
Shrimp toast, gentlemen?
-不 谢谢 -谢谢
- Uh, no, thanks. - Thanks.
你说有个受害人提起了刑事诉讼吗
You said one of the victims filed a criminal complaint?
恩 有一些
Yeah, there were a few of them.
但是教会的同伴起诉后
But the judge had the case records sealed
法官就密封了案件记录
after friends of the church complained.
而且教会的人脉众多
And the church has a lot of friends.
比如埃里克・麦克利什吗
Like Eric macleish?
恩
Yeah.
我只能说他嘴太严了 我们得找别的方法
Let's just say he's not part of the solution.
-你听懂我的意思了吗 -当然
- You follow what I'm saying? - Sure.
你工作真卖力 雷赞德斯先生
You work hard, Mr. Rezendes.
-你结婚了吗 -恩
- Are you married? - Yeah.
你妻子不介意你
Your wife doesn't mind you
-整天工作吗 -噢 她介意
- working all the time? - Oh, yeah, she does.
这就是为什么我没有结婚 我太忙了
That's why I never got married. I'm too busy.
我的工作太重要了
What I do is too important.
恩
Mmm.
你们的新编辑是个犹太人 对吗
Your new editor, he's a Jew, right?
恩 是的
That's right. Yeah.
你看 他一进来
Well, see, he comes in
大家突然都对教会有了兴趣
and suddenly everybody's interested in the church.
你知道为什么吗
You know why? Mmm.
因为他是旁观者清 跟我一样
Because it takes an outsider, like me.
我是亚美尼亚人
I'm Armenian.
你认识多少在波士顿的亚美尼亚人
How many Armenians do you know in Boston?
史蒂夫・柯吉恩 在《环球报》上班
Steve kurkjian. Works at the globe.
噢 你认识两个了 真该给你颁个奖
Oh. That's two. You should get a prize or something.
-你是哪里人 意大利人吗 -不 我是葡萄牙人
- What are you, Italian? - No, I'm Portuguese.
-哪里来的 -波士顿东区
- From where? - Uh, east Boston.
真的吗 波士顿东区
Really? East Boston?
你口音听起来不像啊
You don't sound like it.
这座城市 这些人
This city, these people--
让我们这些外来人觉得没有归属感
making the rest of us feel like we don't belong.
但他们并不比我们优秀
But they're no better than us.
看看他们如何对待孩子的吧
Look at how they treat their children.
记住我的话 雷赞德斯先生
Mark my words, Mr. Rezendes,
环境可以塑造一个孩子
if it takes a village to raise a child,
也可以毁了一个孩子
it takes a village to abuse one.
嘿 你来了
Hey, here he is.
-要喝酒吗 -乐意之至
- Want a beer? - Love one.
再来一杯
Another.
-和芭芭拉一起来的吗 -不 她不喜欢来这些地方
- You here with Barbara? - No, no. She hates these things.
凯伦也是
Karen too. Yeah.
女人真聪明
Smart ladies.
-干杯 -干杯
- Slente. - Slente.
我见到了你的新编辑
Mmm. I met your new editor.
看起来是个不错的人
Seemed like a decent fellow.
我觉得是的
I think he is.
嘿 前些天我和埃里克・麦克利什
Hey, I had an interesting conversation
谈了一些有趣的东西
with Eric macleish the other day.
原来多年来他一直
Turns out he's been settling
在帮总教区调解性侵儿童案
abuse cases with the archdiocese for years.
你真的想在这里谈这个吗
You really want to talk about this here?
吉姆 你说你帮了巴雷特神父当是人情
Jim, you said you helped out on father Barrett as a favor.
只有那一次吗
That was a one-off?
你还参与了多少件案子
How many of these cases you been involved with?
你知道我不能回答 罗比 这是违反职业道德的
You know I can't answer that, robby. It's unethical.
真的仅仅因为这个吗
Is that all it is?
这就是我一直有所耳闻
So, this would be the robby Robinson
但却素未谋面的罗比・罗宾森
I've always heard about but never met.
哈
Huh?
听我说 吉米
Listen to me, Jimmy.
你得选对边
You want to be on the right side of this.
你说的可是教会啊 罗比
This is the church you're talking about, robby.
看看四周 他们都是好人
Look around. These are good people.
为这座城市做了很多好事
Done a lot of good for this city.
你就好好玩吧
Enjoy the party.
我现在看了很多名录
I've been through a lot of these now.
他们将这些神父开除时
"Sick leave" Isn't the only designation they use
不光会声称“休病假”
when they take one of these priests out of circulation.
他们用一堆说法 “未出席”
They use a slew of terms: "Absent on leave,"
“未分配” “应急响应”
"Unassigned," "Emergency response."
-这些人什么词都用上了 -除了强奸
- They got a word for everything, these guys. - Except rape.
而且他们比其他神父更频繁地更换教区
And they move parishes way more frequently than other priests.
在我小时候
When I was a kid, a priest moved
一个神父过了七八年才走 有时候更久
after seven or eight years, sometimes longer.
这些人顶多两三年就走了
These guys, it's two to three years tops.
萨维亚诺说的神父后面都是这么写的吗
And did they use these designations for all of saviano's priests?
恩 这是个很明显的模式
Yeah. It's a pretty clear pattern.
伙计们 赛普打电话来了
Guys, I got sipe.
我觉得如果你们真的想理解这场危机
I think if you really want to understand the crisis,
你们要先从禁欲需求开始着手
you need to start with the celibacy requirement.
那是我的第一个主要发现
That was my first major finding.
只有一半的神父是禁欲的
Only 50% of the clergy are celibate.
现在大多数神父都和其他成人有过性行为
Now, most of them are having sex with other adults.
但这样子却创造了一种容忍甚至是保护
But the fact remains that this creates a culture of secrecy
其中的恋童癖者的风气
that tolerates and even protects pedophiles.
那么你觉得教会知道
So you believe the church
这件事的严重程度吗
is aware of the extent of this, uh, crisis?
噢 当然
Oh, absolutely.
在路易斯安那州首先爆出丑闻后
After the first major scandal in Louisiana,
教廷大使的秘书兼教律学家和汤姆・多伊尔
tom Doyle, the secretary canonist for the papal nuncio,
共同创作了一份报告 警告恋童癖的神父
co-authored a report warning pedophile priests
若犯了此罪 则要承担赔偿上亿美元的法律责任
were a billion-dollar liability.
那是1985年
That was in 1985.
1985年
1985?
是的
That's right.
谁看了那份报告 有天主教会的人吗
Who saw that report? Anyone from the catholic hierarchy?
当然 多伊尔想把这份报告
Sure. Doyle tried to introduce the report
在天主教全国主教会议上公布出来
at the national conference of catholic bishops.
事实上 当时劳主教为这份报告提供了资金
In fact, cardinal law initially helped to fund the report.
但之后他退缩了 然后他们搁置了此事
But then he backed out and they shelved it.
-他在开玩笑吗 -理查德 我是罗比
- Is he kidding me? - Uh, Richard, robby here.
我们觉得波士顿有十三个符合此模式的神父
We think we have 13 priests in Boston that fit this pattern,
这会是一个大新闻
which would be a very-- a very big story.
你觉得有这么多人吗
Does that sound right to you, uh, in terms of scale?
不 罗比 在我看来是太少了
No, not really, robby. Sounds low to me.
我估计至少有百分之六对儿童有过性侵行为
My estimates suggest six percent act out sexually with minors.
百分之六什么
Uh, six percent of what?
百分之六的神父
Six percent of all priests.
波士顿有多少神父
How many priests do we have in Boston?
大概一千五百个 百分之一是十五个
About 1,500. One percent is 15.
百分之六是 九十
Six percent is... 90.
什么 九十个神父
Wait. Nine-ninety priests?
这有可能吗
Is that possible?
从数量上来看 是的
From a metric standpoint, yes.
那和我的发现是一致的
That would certainly be in line with my findings.
-喂 -额
- Hello? - Uh--
波士顿有九十个这样的神父
ninety fucking priests? In Boston?
他是这么说的
That's what he said.
如果有九十个这样的混蛋 人们会知道的
If there were 90 of these bastards, people would know.
也许他们知道
Maybe they do.
但大家都缄默不语吗
And no one said a thing?
大家都是友好的德国人
Good Germans.
我想你这话可不能在外说
I don't think that's a comparison you want to make publicly.
麦克利什知道 他只是什么都没说
Macleish knew. He just didn't say anything.
那是十三个神父
That's 13 priests.
十三和九十之间差别很大的
There's a big difference between 13 and 90.
赛普从哪里得知的这些数字
Where's this guy sipe getting his numbers?
他对此研究了三十年
Well, he's been studying it for 30 years.
-他是一位专业的精神治疗医师 -好的
- He is a trained psychotherapist. - Okay.
但我们不能全都听信一个
But we need something
以前是神父 还和一个尼姑结婚的嬉皮士
more than a metric from some hippie ex-priest
我们还需要更多证据
who's shacking up with a nun.
好 那我们就再找些受害者 这样就能找到更多神父
Okay, so we'll track down more victims. We'll get more priests.
然后我们可以用名录找到他们
Then we could check them against the directories.
-受害者这么多 -我们会找到的
- That's a shitload of victims. - We'll get there.
要多久
How long's it gonna take?
太久了
Too long.
等等 会议结束了吗
Wait. Meeting's over?
目前是的
Yeah, for now.
-你有什么办法 -要是我们反着来呢
- What've you got? - What if we work backwards?
-什么意思 反着做什么 -查名录
- What do you mean? From what? - From the directories.
我们一直在用名录确认行为不端的神父
We've been using them to confirm bad priests.
如果我们反着来呢
What if we do it the other way around?
-用名录来追查行为不端的神父 -正是
- Use the directories to identify bad priests. - Yeah, exactly.
我们去找那些说法
We search by designation. We
找标记着“休病假”或“未分配”的所有神父
look for any priest on "Sick leave" Or "Unassigned."
-或者搬过很多次的神父 -恩
- Or have been moved around a lot. - Yeah.
-那要费很多精力吧 -大家一起干就好了
- It's gonna take a load of work. - Well, not if we're all on it.
你也来吗
You too?
-通常来说 “大家”肯定包含了我啊 -对 通常来说是这样
- Generally that's what "All" Means. - Yeah, generally.
图书馆要关门了
Library is closing.
我擦
Holy shit.
不可能吧
No freakin' way.
-塔尔博特 -恩
- Talbot. - Yep.
-蒂夫南 -恩
- Tivnan. - Yep.
-托马 -恩
- Toma. - Yep.
-特恩布尔 -恩
- Turnbull. - Yep.
-沃尔什 -恩
- Walsh. - Yep.
-威尔斯 恩
- Welsh. - Yep.
-就这些了 -就这些了
- That's it. - That's it.
-天呐 -罗比
- Holy shit. - Robby.
和赛普估计的只差三个 简直难以置信
That's three off sipe's estimate. That's incredible.
罗比
Robby.
-有多少个 -八十七个
- How many? - Eighty-seven.
波士顿有八十七个神父
Eighty-seven priests in Boston.
-给麦克利什打电话 我要找他谈谈 -好
- Call macleish. I wanna talk to him. - Okay.
-能打印出来吗 -当然可以
- Can you print it? - Sure can.
吉姆・苏利文的办公室
Jim Sullivan's office.
我是沃尔特・罗宾森 我找吉姆・苏利文
Yeah, Walter Robinson for Jim Sullivan.
请告诉他有要事 拜托了
Tell him it's important, please.
请稍等
One moment, please.
嘿 罗比 还好吗
Hey, robby. Everything okay?
我要你告诉我一些事情 吉姆
I need you to tell me something, Jim.
-有九十个神父吗 -什么
- Could it be 90 priests? - What?
有九十个神父这么多吗
Could it be as high as 90?
天呐 罗比
Jesus, robby.
我必须得知道 吉姆 如果不重要的话我是不会问的
I need to know, Jim. I wouldn't be asking if it wasn't important.
你得收手了 罗比
You gotta stop this, robby.
罗比 麦克利什的助手说
Robby, macleish's assistant
他时间排满了 没法见我们
said he's all booked up. He can't see us.
好吧 去他的
Yeah. Well, the hell he can't.
好的 这会很有意思的
All right. That'll be fun.
我待会来找你 好吗
You know what? I'll catch up with you, okay?
-好的 -嘿
- Okay. - Hey.
真的很抱歉 我现在没时间谈话
I'm really sorry. I am. I don't have any time to talk right now--
麦克利什先生 我们有理由相信
Mr. Macleish, we have reason to believe
波士顿有八十七位神父
that there are allegations
都受过指控
against as many as 87 priests in Boston.
我不能和你们谈这些
I can't talk to you about that.
-这个数字对吗 -你在开玩笑吧
- Does that number sound right to you? - You gotta be kidding me.
我说过了 我现在没时间闲扯
I just told you I don't have time for this crap now.
埃里克 你调解了多少个神父
Eric, how many priests did you settle?
罗比 你知道我不能告诉你
Robby, you know I can't tell you that.
你得把神父和受害者的名字都给我
You're gonna give me the names and the names of their victims.
额
Um--
你是在威胁我吗
are you threatening me?
我们现在有两条新闻
We've got two stories here.
一条新闻是关于那些可恶的神父
We've got a story about degenerate clergy,
另一条则是关于一帮律师
and we've got a story about a bunch of lawyers
他们把性侵儿童案当成了家庭手工业
turning child abuse into a cottage industry.
你想我们报道哪条新闻
Now, which story do you want us to write?
因为我们必须要选一条
'Cause we're writing one of 'em.
我已经给你寄了一份名单
I already sent you a list of names.
你在说什么 寄给了谁
What are you talking about? To whom?
几年前 寄给了《环球报》
The globe. Years ago.
波特的案子发生后 我接到了很多电话
After the Porter case, I got plenty of calls.
光是波士顿就有二十个牵扯其中的神父
I had 20 priests in Boston alone,
但没有媒体的帮助 我无法调查他们
but I couldn't go after them without the press.
因此我给了你们一份名单
So I sent you guys a list of names,
你们却置若罔闻
and you buried it.
-我明天就要这些名字 -去你的剪报里找吧 罗比
- I want those names tomorrow. - Check your goddamn clips, robby.
-我们在剪报里什么也没找到 -是啊 真让人吃惊
- We didn't find anything in the clips. - Yeah. Big surprise.
理查德 额 你还在做弥撒吗
Richard, uh, do you still go to mass?
不 我已经有一阵子没去教堂了
No. No, I haven't been to church for some time now.
但我还是个天主教徒
But I still consider myself a catholic.
这怎么行得通呢
H-how does that work?
教会是一个由人组成的机构 麦克
Well, the church is an institution, Mike, made of men.
它是短暂的
It's passing.
但我的信仰是永恒的
My faith is in the eternal.
我试着把两者区分开来
I try to separate the two.
-听起来很难 -的确
- Sounds tricky. - It is.
特别是教会还在对我穷追猛打
Especially since the church continues to go after me.
代价很大的 麦克
It takes a toll, Mike.
他们想要镇压所有站出来说话的人
They'll try to silence anyone who speaks out.
我想他们很快就会找上你和你的团队
I'm sure they'll come after you and your team soon enough.
真的吗 那你觉得他们会怎么做
Really. And how do you think they'd do that?
喂
Hello?
理查德
Richard?
谁啊
Who is it?
坎特伯雷大主教
It's the archbishop of canterbury.
我在披萨店吃了晚饭 剩了一些
I had dinner at santarpio's. Had some leftovers.
啊 你太棒了 谢啦
Ah, you're the freakin' best. Thanks.
-要喝酒吗 -要
- You want a beer? - Yeah.
好的
You got it.
天呐 你还要在这个鬼地方住多久
Jesus. How much longer you gonna be in this shithole?
还在想呢
Yeah. I'm working on it.
她是个好女孩 麦克
She's a good girl, Mike.
是的 我们会解决的
Yeah, she is. We'll figure it out.
我最近没什么时间
I haven't had a lot of time lately.
其实我刚刚才和赛普通完电话
I just got off the phone with sipe, actually.
你亲眼见过这个人吗
Have you met this guy in person yet?
没有 不过他对此事的了解明显跟我们不在一个层次
No, but his knowledge of this is on a whole other level.
我要饿死了
I'm frickin' starving.
九十个神父的事查得怎么样了
So, where are we with the 90?
快了
We're close.
-多快 -就是快了
- How close? - We're close.
直接回答问题 好吗
Just answer the question, will you?
我们查到了八十七个
We got 87 names.
正在努力确认 我们会查清楚的
We're trying to get confirmation. I think we will.
你在心烦什么
Something bugging you?
我只是很惊讶
It's just surprising, that's all.
恩 是啊
Yeah. Yeah, it is.
大家都是
For everybody.
等等 本 我忘了问你
Wait, Ben. I forgot to ask you.
菲尔・萨维亚诺说
Phil saviano said he sent
几年前他给《环球报》寄了一些资料
a bunch of info over to the globe years ago.
-你知道寄给谁了吗 -不知道 怎么了
- Do you have any idea to who? - No. Why?
我好奇罢了 我想知道
I'm just curious. I wanted to
你们有没有漏掉什么线索
see if there's any leads you guys didn't run out.
萨维亚诺五年前是个
Saviano was a fucking train
操蛋的麻烦鬼 我们没有漏了什么
wreck five years ago. We didn't miss anything.
这件事得有聚焦的追查
This story needed spotlight.
对 我同意 我只是在跟踪调查
Yeah, I agree. I'm just following up.
-晚安 -嗯 晚安
- Good night. - Yeah, good night.
难以置信 你什么时候搞到这个的
This is unbelievable. When did you get this?
麦克利什今天早上发邮件给我的
Macleish e-mailed the list this morning.
他处理了涉及四十五个神父的案件
He settled cases against 45 priests.
我们追查劳的事怎么样了
Where are we on Law?
有线索显示他知道这件事吗
Anything that shows he had knowledge of this?
我们还在对付加拉贝迪安 但没有具体消息
We're still working garabedian. But nothing concrete.
我一直在想我们那天晚上的对话
I keep thinking about that conversation we had the other night
关于在我们报道波特案的时候
about how Law called down the power of god
劳是如何借用神的力量的
when we reported on Porter.
那就是劳的本性
That's just Law being Law.
好吧 但我查了剪报
Okay. But I checked the clips, and,
呃 波特甚至都不在波士顿教区
uh, Porter isn't even in the Boston archdiocese.
他来自福尔里弗市 所以 为什么反应这么激烈
He's from fall river. So... why the extreme reaction?
劳肯定知道
Law had to know.
所以他的反应才这么激烈
That's why he had the reaction.
因为他知道还有其他人
Because he knew there were others.
我觉得这就是我要的更重要的故事
I think that's the bigger story.
等等 比五十个神父还重要吗
Wait. Bigger than 50 priests?
如果它是至上而下的操作 是的
If it came from the top down, yes.
但这数字明显
But the numbers clearly
暗示了还有更高级的神职人员牵扯进去
indicate that there were senior clergy involved.
但是现在这些也只能是暗示
That's all they do-- indicate.
你是说如果我们
Are you telling me that if we
发表波士顿有五十个恋童癖神父的报道
run a story with 50 pedophile priests in Boston--
麦克
Mike.
我们就会陷入跟你报道波特案后一样的激烈争论
We'll get into the same catfight you got into on Porter,
除了制造噪音之外完全没有改变任何事情
which made a lot of noise but changed things not one bit.
我们得把注意力集中在教会机构 而不是个别神父
We need to focus on the institution, not the individual priests.
惯例跟政策
Practice and policy.
你们得让我看到教会操纵了司法体系
Show me the church manipulated the system
所以这些家伙才得以逃脱指控
so that these guys wouldn't have to face charges.
要让我看到他们一次又一次地
Show me they put those same priests back into parishes
把同一批神父塞回教区
time and time again.
让我看到这是一个体系的 从上而下的
Show me this was systemic, that it came from the top down.
听起来我们是要对付劳啊
Sounds like we're going after law.
我们是要追查这个体系
We're going after the system.
列一张我们目前掌握的所有受害人的清单 开始行动吧
Make a list of all the victims we have. Start reaching out.
-如果需要帮助可以把马特请来 -嗯哼 好的
- And bring Matt in if you need help. - Mm-hmm. Okay.
-嘿 你什么时候去斯普林菲尔德 -我们的听证会是在周一
- Hey, when do you go to Springfield? - Our hearing is Monday.
好的
Okay.
喂 罗比 你有时间吗
Hey, robby, you got a second?
有的
Yeah.
我 离我家一个街区的地方
I, uh-- I got one of those
有个治疗中心
treatment centers a block from my house.
周围的邻居都有小孩
We got neighbors with kids.
我知道我们的工作是机密
I know that the work we do is confidential,
但我觉得 我应该告诉他们
but I'm feeling like... I should tell 'em.
我们很快就会告诉他们了
We'll tell 'em soon.
你确定
You sure?
-对 -好吧
- Yeah. - Okay.
嗨 我是萨夏・法伊弗 《波士顿环球报》的
Hi there. I'm sacha pfeiffer. I'm with the Boston globe.
我正在找一位名为马修・沃尔什的先生
I'm just looking for a gentleman by the name of Matthew Walsh.
呃 不 他不是
Uh, no, he's not.
-就在那边 -好的 好
- Right there. - Yeah. Okay. Okay.
-你好 -你好
- Hi. - Hi.
我是《波士顿环球报》的萨夏・法伊弗
I'm sacha pfeiffer from the Boston globe.
-哦 你有什么事 -我想跟托马斯・肯尼迪谈谈
- Yeah, what do you want? - I'd like to speak with Thomas Kennedy.
-他已经不住这里了 -那你知道他住哪吗
- He doesn't live here anymore. - Do you know where he lives?
先生 我只是想问几个
Sir, I'd just like to ask a few--
我是萨夏・法伊弗 《波士顿环球报》的
sacha pfeiffer, Boston globe.
-噢 是 你好 -你好 谢谢
- Oh, yeah. Hi. - Hi. Thank you.
-你还能想到什么其他事吗 -没了
- Anything else you can recall? - No.
想不起了 不过我有个堂姐在昆西
No, but I got a cousin in Quincy.
她几年后在街上见过他
She saw him in the street a few years later.
主教走进了房子
The bishop came to the house.
他说之前从没发生过这样的事情
He said nothing like this had ever happened before.
他叫我们不要起诉
He asked us not to press charges.
那你母亲是怎么做的
And what did your mother do?
我母亲
My mother?
她居然还拿出了饼干招待
She put out freakin' cookies.
当时有很大的压力让我们保持沉默
There was a lot of pressure to keep quiet.
-来自教会的压力吗 -对 来自教会的
- From the church? - Yeah, from the church.
但不只是教会
But not just the church.
还有我的朋友
From my friends.
其他的教区居民
From the other parishioners.
嗯 我治疗的很多神父
Well, many of the priests that I treated
都是性心理发育不良
were psychosexually stunted.
情感方面还停留在十二三岁的水平
On the emotional level of a 12- or 13-year-old.
天啊
Jesus.
首领主教当然知道 每个人都知道
Sure the chief knew. Everybody knew.
但没有人想给神父戴上手铐
But nobody wants to cuff a priest.
嗯 那公诉人呢
Mmm. And what about the prosecutor?
-我不该谈这件破事 -其实我觉得你应该
- I shouldn't talk about this shit. - I think you should, actually.
你认识赫尔利神父或者盖尔神父吗
Do you know a father Hurley or a father Gale?
认识
I do.
-我会把你打得屁滚尿流 -抱歉打扰你了
- I'll beat the shit out of you. - Sorry to bother you.
你不要再来了 不要再来
You leave me alone. You leave
打扰我兄弟 听到了吗 该死的
my brother alone. You hear me? Goddamn it.
你好 我找罗纳德・帕奎因
Hi there. I'm looking for Ronald paquin.
怎么了
Yes?
-你就是帕奎因神父吗 -是的 没错
- You're father paquin? - Yes. That's right.
我是《波士顿环球报》的萨夏・法伊弗 我
I'm sacha pfeiffer from the Boston globe. I--
-好的 -我能问你几个问题吗
- okay. - Could I ask you a few questions?
问吧 亲爱的
Go ahead, dear.
我们跟几个小时候在黑弗里尔的圣约翰浸信会
We spoke to several men who knew you when they were boys
就认识你的人谈过
at St. John the baptist in haverhill.
他们说你曾性骚扰过他们 这是真的吗
Did-- they told us you molested them. Is that true?
嗯 当然 我胡闹过
Mmm, sure, I fooled around.
但我自己从未感到开心过
But I never felt gratified myself.
这样 嗯
Right. Um--
但你承认在圣约翰浸信会性骚扰过男孩子们
but you admit to molesting boys at St. John the baptist?
对对 但就像我说的 我从来没得到过任何快感
Yes, yes, but as I said, I never got any pleasure from it.
了解这一点是很重要的
That's important to understand.
好的
Right.
嗯 但你能告诉我
Um, but can you tell me
你是在哪里 又是怎么玩弄那些男孩子的
where and how you fooled around with these boys?
我要说清楚一点 我从来没有强暴过任何人
I want to be clear. I never raped anyone.
这是不一样的 我是知道的
There's a difference. I should know.
-你怎么知道的 -我就被强暴过
- How would you know? - I was raped.
我很抱歉 是谁强暴了你
I'm sorry. Who raped you?
-罗尼 你在跟谁讲话 -没事的 简
- Ronny, who are you talking to? - It's okay, Jane.
-帕奎因神父 谁强暴了你 -你是谁
- Father paquin, who raped you? - Who are you?
呃 我是萨夏・法伊弗 《环球报》的
Uh, sacha pfeiffer, from the globe.
-请离开我的走廊 -我能自己说话
- Please get off my porch. - I can speak for myself.
-回房去 罗恩 -先生
- Get inside the house, Ron. - Mr.--
-进去 罗恩 -好吧
- get inside, Ron. - Okay.
-抱歉 您是 -我是他妹妹
- I'm sorry. Who are you? - I'm his sister.
-并且我希望你不要再回来这里了 -帕奎因小姐
- And I don't want you coming back here. - Miss paquin--
我会在街尾超过你的
beat you to the end of the street.
-不可能 -我上次就超过你了
- No, you won't. - I beat you last time.
才没有 你作弊了
No, you didn't. You cheated. You did.
能请你为我阐明一下《环球报》的态度吗 阿尔巴诺先生
Could you please clarify the globe's position for me, Mr. Albano?
好的 斯威尼法官
Yes, judge sweeney.
我们关于公开这些文件的论证
Our argument to make these documents public
主要是基于第一修正案的
rests mainly on first amendment grounds.
我们还有一些其他相关的论证
We also have a number of other relevant arguments.
法官阁下 毕竟这是个自由裁量指令
After all, your honor, this was a discretionary order.
是的 它取决于法官的裁量
Yes. It was made at the judge's discretion.
嘿 麦克
Hey, Mike.
嗨 乔
Hey, Joe.
聚焦的记者来到斯普林菲尔德做什么
What's a spotlight reporter doing in Springfield?
你的阿尔巴诺正在逆水行舟
Your boy albano's sledding uphill.
你真的觉得你们有机会赢这场官司吗
You actually think you have a shot at winning this thing?
你想让我对《先驱报》发表评论吗
You want me to comment for the herald?
“环球报记者不予置评
"Globe reporter would not comment,
但他看起来不抱希望”
but he did not seem hopeful."
他完全不试图隐瞒
He didn't try and hide it at all.
他有相当奇怪的合理化说法
He had this really odd rationalization for it,
好像玩弄小男孩是完全正常的事情
like it was totally normal to fool around with little boys.
我真的很想回去 我觉得他会愿意跟我们谈谈
I'd really like to go back. I think he'd talk to us.
噢 我们会的
Oh, we will.
只是时机未到
Just not yet.
我希望你现在继续重点关注受害者们
I want you to stay focused on the victims right now.
萨夏 他们把塔尔伯特神父送到哪了
Sacha, where'd they send father Talbot again?
呃 好像是 舍沃罗斯
Um, I think-- wasn't that cheverus?
舍沃罗斯 没错 等等
Cheverus. That's right. Wait.
塔尔伯特是波士顿天主教高中的吗
Father Talbot from bc high?
对 你认识他吗
Yeah. You know him?
嗯 我们是同一时期读的中学
Yeah. He was there when I was.
-是受害者吗 -对 住在普罗维登斯
- We have a victim? - Yeah. Lives in Providence.
这些文件都无关个人 法官阁下
There's nothing personal in these documents, your honor.
他们是关于红衣主教怎么处理
They concern how the cardinal is handling--
请说“总教区”
say "The archdiocese."
什么
Excuse me?
你不能把所有事都归为红衣主教的所为 阿尔巴诺先生
You don't get to tag the cardinal with everything, Mr. Albano.
请说“总教区”
Say "The archdiocese."
斯威尼法官 《环球报》不是
Judge sweeney, the globe is not a
本案相关的任何一方 他们只是想增加销量罢了
party to this case. They just want to sell papers.
如果加拉贝迪安先生没有诋毁主教的清名
If Mr. Garabedian had not smeared the cardinal's good name,
我们也不会在这里了
we wouldn't even be here.
法官阁下 我反对使用“诋毁”这个词
Your honor, I object to the use of the word "Smear."
-已悉 加拉贝迪安先生 -谢谢 法官阁下
- Duly noted, Mr. Garabedian. - Thank you, your honor.
-还有吗 罗杰斯先生 -没了 法官阁下
- Anything else, Mr. Rogers? - No, your honor.
阿尔巴诺先生 您请继续
Mr. Albano, you may continue.
《环球报》认为
The globe believes having--
喂 米奇 最近好吗
hey, Mitch, how you doing?
挺好的
I'm fine.
他挺难搞的啊 那个威尔逊・罗杰斯
He's tough, that Wilson Rogers.
他太自以为是 还很马虎
He's smug. And he's sloppy.
看起来不马虎啊
He doesn't seem sloppy.
你没有我知道的多 相信我
You don't know the half of it. Trust me.
你还知道什么
What's the half of it?
告诉我啊 米奇
Tell me the half of it, Mitch.
-私底下讲吗 -对 偷偷告诉我
- Off the record? - Off the record, yeah.
三年前 我接到一个前神父的电话
Three years ago, I get a call from an ex-priest.
安东尼・本泽维奇
Anthony benzevich.
他在62年的圣餐礼上
He was at blessed sacrament back in '62,
看到吉欧根
and he saw geoghan...
把小男孩们带进管区卧室
Taking little boys up to the rectory bedroom, okay?
他觉得很震惊 然后就告诉了主教
So he's appalled, all right? Tells the bishop about it.
然后主教威胁要把他派到南美
And the bishop threatens to reassign him to south America.
-老天 -对 没错
- Jesus. - Yeah, all right.
所以快进三十五年 本泽维奇在报上看到
So fast-forward 35 years, benzevich reads
吉欧根被指控对数百个孩子进行过性骚扰
that geoghan has been charged with molesting hundreds of kids.
然后他感到内疚 给我打了电话
All right? So he feels guilty. He calls me.
所以你手里有一份神父
So you have testimony of a priest
在62年向他上级举报吉欧根的证词吗
telling his superiors about geoghan in '62?
不 我没有
No, I do not.
因为我让本泽维奇来做宣誓证词的时候
Because when I called benzevich in to give a deposition,
他带了个律师过来
he comes in with a lawyer.
-威尔逊・罗杰斯 -对
- Wilson Rogers. - Right.
然后本泽维奇神父就突然变得记忆模糊了
And suddenly father benzevich has a very foggy memory.
什么也不记得了 没用了
Can't remember anything. He's useless.
所以我就回去工作 忘了这件事
So I go back to work. I forget about it. Whatever.
直到一年前 我找到一篇文章
Until about a year ago, I find an article
是讲有一个神父警告教会注意吉欧根的事
about a priest who warned church officials about geoghan.
-本泽维奇去找了媒体吗 -对
- Benzevich went to the press? - Yeah.
对 当地报纸 叫做《爱国者纪事报》 没人看到
Yeah. Local paper, patriot ledger. Nobody saw it.
但我有本泽维奇的公开声明了
But now I got benzevich on record.
所以我提出动议让本泽维奇再次宣誓作证
So I file a motion to depose benzevich a second time. All right?
然后威尔逊・罗杰斯 那个自以为是的王八蛋
And Wilson Rogers, that smug son of a bitch,
他提了个动议来反对我的动议
he files a motion opposing my motion.
就是那时候我抓住了他的把柄
And that's when I have him.
把柄 什么把柄
Have-- have him how?
罗杰斯反对我的动议 所以我得做个论证
Rogers opposes my motion, so I have to make an argument
证明为什么要允许
as to why I'm allowed to
我再次请本泽维奇神父作证
depose father benzevich a second time, okay?
但是这次 我可以附加上一些证据
But this time, I'm allowed to attach exhibits.
你明白我在说什么吗
Do you follow what I'm saying?
-附加上那些密封文件吗 -对
- The sealed documents? - Yes.
我可以附上
I can attach the sealed documents
我发现的密封文件 雷赞德斯先生
that I've gotten in discovery, Mr. Rezendes,
就是你们报社现在在找的那些文件
the same documents that your paper is currently suing for.
你在唬我
You're shitting me.
什么 不不 我没骗你
What? No. No, I'm not shitting you.
所以我调出十四份最确凿的文件
So I pull out the 14 most damning docs
把它们附加到我的动议里
and I attach them to my motion.
这样就能证明了一切 一切
And they prove everything. Everything.
关于教会 关于主教 关于劳
About the church, about the bishops, about Law.
而这是全部公开的吗
And it's all public?
因为你反对罗杰动议的动议
Because your motion to oppose Roger's motion--
是公开的
is public.
对 就是这样 现在你终于注意到了
Yeah. Exactly. Now you're paying attention.
所以我现在能直接走进法院
So I could just walk into that
拿到那些文件吗
courthouse right now and get those documents?
不 不行 因为那些文件不在法院
No, you cannot, because the documents are not there.
但你刚才说它们是公开的
But you just said they're public.
我是说过 但这里是波士顿
I know I did. But this is Boston.
而教会并不希望有人找到它们
And the church does not want them to be found.
所以它们不在那里
So they are not there.
米奇 你是说天主教会
Mitch, are you telling me that the catholic church
能从法院移走法律文件吗
removed legal documents from that courthouse?
听着 我没疯 也没得妄想症
Look, I'm not crazy. I'm not paranoid.
我是有处世经验的人
I'm experienced.
查查档案记事表 你就明白了
Check the docket. You'll see.
他们什么都能操纵
They control everything.
什么都能
Everything.
我得回去了
I gotta go back in.
我得赶紧去拿那些该死的文件
I just got the fucking documents.
诉讼事件表流水号49 吉欧根案
Docket entry number 49, in the geoghan case.
-好的 谢谢 -我们十分钟后关门
- Okay, thanks. - We close in 10 minutes.
十分钟 好的
Ten minutes? All right.
罗比
Robby.
嘿 你绝对不会相信
Hey. You're not gonna believe it.
加拉贝迪安给了我一个提示
Garabedian gave me a tip.
有一些密封文件已经公开了
Some of the sealed docs are already public.
它们是他申请的动议的一部分
They're part of a motion he filed.
他说它们是文件中的精华
He said they're the best of the bunch.
我们不必等斯威尼的裁决了
We don't have to wait for sweeney's ruling.
-所以我们能搞到它们吗 -对 但它们不在那里
- So we can get them? - Yeah, but they're not there.
已经跟阿尔巴诺谈过了
Already talked to albano.
他说我们要做的就是提出动议
He said all we have to do is file a motion,
斯威尼就会让米奇重新归档那些文件
and sweeney will order Mitch to refile the docs.
你觉得那些文件是
And you think these documents are--
他说那十四份文件正是我们需要的 非常重要
he said these 14 docs are all we need. They're huge.
好吧
Okay.
我会打给本 做得很好
I'll call Ben. Good work.
这是纯粹的意外
Is this purely an accident
还是有意的行为
or could this have been an intentional act?
无论如何 这座建筑都受到了重大的损坏
Either way, extensive damage has been done to this building.
怎么回事
What happened?
他们说是一架支持机 但那根本不是
They're saying it's a prop plane, but that's not a prop plane.
叫琳达马上把在这儿的所有记者都召集过来
Tell Linda to get every reporter we have in here now.
我们要为受害者祈祷
You pray for the victims.
要为伤者祈祷
You pray for the injured.
要为幸存者祈祷
And you pray for those who survived.
还要为这个国家祈祷
You pray, too, for the nation.
希望我们对此的回应
That our response to this
能反映出我国最崇高的理想
might reflect the best ideals of our nation.
甚至能反映出上帝的教义
And even more, reflect god's own teaching,
不仅表现在基督教和犹太教
not only as it's shown in christianity and judaism
还有伊斯兰教
but in islam as well.
-说的不错 谁在那里 -保尔森
- Not bad. Who's there? - Paulson.
等他回来后我想跟他谈谈
I wanna talk to him when he's back.
雷赞德斯找到方法去佛罗里达了吗
Did rezendes find a way to get to Florida yet?
他们刚开放了普罗维登斯的机场
They just opened the airport in Providence.
他正在过去的路上
He's on his way there now.
本 我需要多点人在港务局
Ben, I'm gonna need more people on massport.
我会派给你三个人
I'll give you three of my guys.
-罗比 你的团队也去负责这事 -收到
- Robby, put your team on that too. - Got it.
-还有 罗比 其他的事都先放到一边 -明白
- And, robby, everything else stops. - Understood.
麦克为什么要去佛罗里达
Why is Mike going to Florida?
去航校 那是他们学开飞机的地方
Flight school. It's where they learned to fly.
罗比 我这周安排了好多受害者要采访
Robby, I've got a lot of victim interviews set up this week.
你得取消了
You're gonna have to cancel 'em.
-这会很艰难 -我知道 简直疯了
- That's gonna be hard. - I know. This is nuts.
两天前我跟我老婆说我们
Two days ago I told my wife we
会报道一起全世界最爆炸性的新闻
gotta be working the biggest story on the planet.
《波士顿环球报》
Boston globe.
《波士顿环球报》 请稍等
Boston globe. One moment, please.
是的 如果您有什么消息 我会帮您转到《都市报》
Yes, if you have a tip, I will transfer you down to Metro.
我是米切尔・加拉贝迪安
Mitchell garabedian.
米奇 我是麦克 我一直想联系你
Mitch, it's Mike. I've been trying to reach you.
我没有时间和你说话 雷赞德斯先生
I don't have time to talk to you, Mr. Rezendes.
很快就好 你重新归档那些文件了吗
Hey, just quickly. Did you refile those docs yet?
没有 我刚接到传令 还需要点时间
No. I just got the order. It takes time.
-好的 很好 你能拖延一下归档时间吗 -为什么
- Okay, great. Can you hold off on refiling them? - Hold off?
我得去一趟佛罗里达 你一归档它们就公开了
I have to go to Florida. Once you refile they're public.
其他报纸也能得到它们
Other newspapers will be able to get a hold of 'em.
其他报纸什么的我不关心
Other newspapers are not my concern.
我收到了裁决令
I received a judicial order.
我跟你说了教会正盯着我
I told you the church is watching me.
喂 米奇 拜托你 我只需要几周时间
Hey, Mitch, please. All I need is a few more weeks.
我不敢保证 再见
I can't make any promises. Good-bye.
米奇 米奇 妈的
Mitch! Mitch! Shit!
靠
Shit.
听着 我算是明白了
Look, I get it.
没人想看到关于
No one wants to read about
儿童被神父强暴的新闻 尤其是现在
kids getting raped by priests, especially now.
但你让那么多人
But you asked a lot of people
回忆了一些非常痛苦的经历 然后就消失了
to relive some very painful experiences, and you just disappear.
菲尔 你知道我们为什么得暂停这个报道
Phil, you know why we were taken off of this story.
九・一一都过去六个星期了
It's been six weeks since 9/11.
我知道 我们会重新追踪这件事的
I realize that, and we're gonna get back to it.
什么时候
When?
-你们还是会跟上次一样 -不是的
- You're doing the same thing you guys did last time. - No.
-你们准备放弃了 -不会的
- You're dropping us. - No.
也许我该把这件事告诉《先驱报》
Maybe I should tell the herald that story.
好吧 菲尔 你去吧
Okay, Phil, you go ahead and do that.
这样我们目前的成果全都会付之一炬 但我阻止不了你
It'll undo all the work we've done, but I can't stop you.
听我说 我会来这里是因为我在乎
Listen to me. I am here because I care.
我们不会放弃的
We're not going away.
我们会不偏不倚地 把这件事公诸于众
We're gonna tell this story. We're gonna tell it right.
我们只是还需要一点时间 这是我们全部的请求
We just need a little more time. That's all we're asking for.
何必请求呢
Why bother asking?
不管怎样你们都会想干什么就干什么
You're gonna do what you want anyway.
你们总是这样
You always do.
菲尔
Phil.
Phil!
喂
Hey.
-南海滩怎么样 -是博因顿海滩 非常不同的地方
- How's South Beach? - Boynton beach. Remarkably different place.
怎么了
What's up?
米奇・加拉贝迪安今天联系我了
Mitch garabedian called me today.
-他为什么打给你 -因为知道你会吼他
- Why'd he call you? - 'Cause he knew you'd yell at him.
-他重新归档了那些文件 -什么
- He refiled the docs. - What?
罗比 那些文件现在是公开的了
Robby, those docs are public now.
我们得在别人之前赶过去
We gotta get there before anyone else does.
我知道 我知道 我知道
I know. I know. I know.
赶紧把手头上的事结束掉 去赶最早的航班
Just wrap up whatever you're doing and get the first flight out.
我现在就订票
I'll book a flight now
明天直接去法院
and go straight to the courthouse tomorrow.
-好的 进去之后通知我 -好的
- All right. Call me when you get in. - Okay.
罗比 我想让菲尔・萨维亚诺知道我们又重新着手这件事了
Robby, I'd like to let Phil saviano know that we're back on it.
好主意
Good idea.
跟汉西吃晚饭去吧 这可能会是很长时间以来的最后一次了
Go have dinner with Hansi. Might be the last time for a while.
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
罗比 我们见过麦克利什之后
Robby, after we saw macleish,
我就开始重新看那些剪报
I started going back through the clips.
上周终于有了点时间
And I had a little time last week finally.
所以 嗯 我找到了这个
So, um, I found that.
这是93年的
It's from '93.
就这个吗
That it?
对对 就 就这个
Yeah. Yeah, that's-- that's it.
晚安
Good night.
好的 晚安
Okay. Good night.
你好
Hello.
所以 我大概比您小几岁 是吗
So, I was probably a few years after you, right?
不 你比我小多了
No, you were more than a few.
相信我
Believe me.
嗯 离开波士顿天主教高中之后 我去了普罗维登斯
Well, after bc high, I came down to Providence
为修道士们打曲棍球
and played hockey for the friars.
哦 你一定表现得很不错
Oh, well, you must have been pretty good.
不不 这水平在大学里就只能坐冷板凳
No. Rode the bench in college. Yeah.
但我爱这座城市
But I loved the city.
啊哈 而且我们刚刚有了第三个孩子
Uh-huh. And we just had our third kid.
而且提醒你一下 我还在看《环球报》
And I still get my globe, for the record.
啊 那很好 挺好的
Ah, that's good to know. Good to know.
听着 凯文 呃 其实我来这里的原因
Look, Kevin, uh, that's actually why I'm here.
-嗯 -我
- Yeah? - I...
我想问你几个关于塔尔伯特神父的问题
I need to ask you some questions about father Talbot.
你怎么发现的
How'd you find out?
这个 呃
Well-- um--
我想这个应该不重要了
I guess it doesn't matter.
呵 我连我老婆都没说过
Hell, I never even told my wife.
借过
Excuse me.
嘿 嘿 嘿 我得进去
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey. I need to get in there.
-我们关门了 -拜托 让我进去 五分钟就好
- We're closed. - Come on. Let me in. Five minutes.
-抱歉 我们关门了 -拜托 五分钟就好
- I'm sorry. We're closed. - Come on. Five minutes.
给 好了
Here. There.
-这是关于吉欧根案的吗 -没错
- This is the geoghan case? - That's right.
-那些文件是密封的 -不 现在有个公开的动议
- Those records are sealed. - No. That's a public motion.
那些文件现在是公开的
Those records are public.
-我是《环球报》的 -挺行的啊
- Look, I work for the globe. - Good for you.
-我可以跟你的主管谈谈吗 -他今天不在
- Can I talk to your supervisor? - He's not in today.
那法官呢
What about a judge? There
一定有法官在处理这类事情的
must be judges that work on this kind of thing.
在六楼
Sixth floor.
我们明白对塔尔伯特神父的
We understand the nature
指控到底是怎么一回事
of the allegations against father Talbot.
我只是不知道你们想从科莫扎校长身上问出些什么
I'm just not sure what you want from president kemeza.
比尔接手的时候塔尔伯特已经离开很久了
Talbot taught here long before bill took over.
嗯 当然
Mmm. Of course.
我们只是想知道是不是
We just want to know if it's possible
包括校长 教职人员 董事会在内
that the president, the faculty, the board,
都没人知道那时候发生了什么
that no one knew what was going on at the time.
我1979年毕业的
I graduated in 1979,
但我完全不知道有这些事
and I had no idea about any of this.
所以如果你是在暗示吉本斯神父和
So if you're suggesting that father Gibbons
卡拉汉神父有任何方面的
and father Callahan had in any way--
吉本斯和卡拉汉
Gibbons and Callahan.
我是说 他们像管海军一样管理这个地方
I mean, they ran this place like the Navy.
你真的觉得他们不知道吗
You really think they didn't know?
这间学校大得很 罗比 你知道的
It's a big school, robby. You know that.
现在我们说的是七个所谓的
And then we're talking about
受害者 还是差不多八年前的事吗
seven alleged victims over, what, eight years?
不 我们现在知道的有七个
No, we're talking about, you know, seven that we know about.
太荒谬了
This is ridiculous.
-你们是在这里挖新闻 -杰克 杰克
- You're reaching for a story here-- - Jack. Jack.
杰克 如果我是那时候的校长 我会知道的
Jack. If I had been president then, I would've known.
比尔 我不确定这有没有关系
Bill, I'm not sure that's relevant.
不然你觉得他们为什么把塔尔伯特送到舍沃罗斯
Why do you think they sent Talbot up to cheverus?
你知道他们想让他离开这里
You know they wanted him out of town.
罗比
Robby,
就像比尔所说的 出于好意
as well intentioned as bill's remarks are,
我希望在达成共识之前
I'm hoping we can keep this
这件事能先保密
between us until we all get on the same page.
这就是我们来这里的原因吗 达成共识
Is that why we're here, to get on the same page?
不 我们来这里是因为你是
No, we're here because you're
一名重要的校友 罗比 也是朋友
an important alumnus, robby, and a friend.
正是 而且我们知道你跟我们一样关心这所学校
Exactly. And we know you care about this school as much as we do.
你在这里参加过体育运动吗 杰克
Did you play a sport here, Jack?
嗯 足球 怎么了
Yeah. Football. Why?
嗯 我参加的是田径
Mmm. I ran track.
我昨天去普罗维登斯
You know, I went to Providence yesterday
跟塔尔伯特神父的受害者谈过
to talk to one of father Talbot's victims.
他在这里打曲棍球 而且打得不错
He played hockey here. And he's one of the better ones.
他娶了老婆 有孩子 事业有成
He's got a wife, kids, good job.
在大概十分钟的深入谈话之后
About 10 minutes into the conversation,
他失控了
the guy breaks down.
哭个不停
You know, couldn't stop crying.
说他一直想不通塔尔伯特神父为什么会选中他
Said he could never figure out why father Talbot picked him.
塔尔伯特神父是曲棍球队的教练
Father Talbot coached the hockey team.
所以
So...
我想我们比较幸运
I guess we just got lucky.
你跟我都是
You and me.
杰克・邓恩在这学校工作吗
Does Jack Dunn work for the school?
没有 他是波士顿大学的公关
No, he's PR for Boston college.
他们需要帮助的时候就会找他
They call him when they need help.
那皮特・康利呢 他为什么在这儿
And Pete conley, why was he there?
问得好 皮特是位重要校友
Good question. Pete's a big alum.
但我直接联系比尔 请求坐下来详谈的
But I called bill directly and I asked for a sit-down.
我没提到过其他任何人
I never mentioned anybody else.
好像每个人都已经知道这件事了
It's like everybody already knows the story.
-对 除了我们 -而我们就在那里工作
- Yeah. Except us. - And we work right there.
-沃尔泰拉法官 -是的
- Judge volterra? - Yes?
你好 我是《波士顿环球报》的记者麦克・雷赞德斯
Hi. I'm Mike Rezendes from the Boston Globe.
我想查阅资料室的
I'm having some trouble accessing
一些公开材料 但遇到了点困难
some public records down in the records room.
我能否与你谈谈
I was wondering if I could have a word with you?
-好的  -谢谢
-All right. -Thank you.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
我得跟你说 雷赞德斯先生
These exhibits you're after, Mr. Rezendes,
这些材料可是敏感的很
they're very sensitive records.
无意冒犯 法官先生 但这不是问题所在
With all due respect, your honor, that's not the question.
这些材料是公开的
The records are public.
也许吧 那你跟我讲讲
Maybe so, but tell me,
新闻记者有什么责任
where's the editorial responsibility
把这些记录公诸于众呢
in publishing records of this nature?
那新闻记者又有什么责任
Well, where's the editorial
不把这些记录公诸于众呢
responsibility in not publishing them?
你不能把这带走 你得去复印一份
You can't take those. You need to make copies.
-我这就去复印室  -那里四点钟就关门了
-I'm going to the copy room. -It closed at 4:00.
听着 我给你
Look, I'll give you...
八十三块 借用你的复印机
83 bucks to use yours.
嘿 出租车
Hey! Cabbie!
嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
到莫里西大道的波士顿环球报大楼
Take me to the Boston Globe on morrissey boulevard.
别走九十三大道 走多切斯特大道
Don't take 93. Take Dorchester Avenue.
罗比 这太不可思议了
Robby, it's incredible.
劳早就知道吉欧根的事了 这点毫无疑问
Law knew about Geoghan for years, no question.
有一名叫做玛格丽特・加兰特的女士给劳寄过一封信
There's a letter to law from a woman, Margaret Gallant,
她在上世纪八十年代初
who lived in Jamaica Plain
居住在牙买加平原 那时吉欧根是那里的神父
in the early '80s when geoghan was there.
听听这个
Listen to this.
“教会是我们家庭的根
"Our family is rooted in the church.
哪怕身处痛苦之中 我们也竭力
Our desire is to protect the holy orders
维护着圣职
even in the midst of our agony
隐瞒了家族中七个男孩被侵犯的事实”
over the seven boys in our family who have been violated."
七个啊 罗比 七个男孩
Seven, robby. Seven boys.
“我们被迫保持沉默
"It was suggested we keep silent.
我们从未质疑过教会的权威
We did not question the authority of the church two years ago.
直到两年前 我得知神父吉欧根还在他的教区任职”
But since Father Geoghan is still in his parish--"
她把这封信寄给了劳 却完全被无视了
but she sent it to law and law did shit.
这儿还有一封寄给劳的信 同一年的 听着
Here's another one to law, same year. Listen to this.
“针对最近教会将神父吉欧根委派至
"A word on the recent assignment of father Geoghan...
韦斯顿的圣朱丽亚教区一事 我有话要说
As an associate at St. Julia's in Weston.
神父吉欧根曾有过
Father Geoghan has a history
性侵男童的记录
of homosexual involvement with young boys.
我想他最近被调离圣布兰登教区
I understand his recent departure from St. Brendan's
也与此有关
may be related to this problem.
我能否请求教区
I wonder if Father Geoghan
撤销对其的降职处理
should not be reduced to just weekend work
而让他接受治疗
while receiving some kind of therapy.
对于您长期以来的关怀我感激不尽
You know how grateful I am to you for your constant concern.
愿主保佑您
Sincerely yours in our lord,
尊敬的主教大人约翰・M・达西 波士顿副主教上
most reverend John M D'arcy, auxiliary bishop of Boston.
一九八四年十二月七日”
December 7, 1984."
这是一个副主教写的信吗
An auxiliary bishop wrote that?
这太令人震惊了
That's incredible.
他越级了 我是说 加兰特是什么时候写的信
He broke ranks. I mean, when did Gallant write her letter?
1984年 劳直接无视了
1984. And law just ignored it.
这样的信怎么能无视呢
How do you ignore that freakin' letter?
但我们拿到了
We got 'em.
看了这些信 我们不能想别的了 这是证据啊
You can't read these letters and think anything else. It's proof.
是啊 没错
Yeah, it is.
这很好
This is good work.
我们要不要把它交给本
Should we take it up to Ben?
呃 不 暂时不要
Uh, no. Not yet.
为什么不呢 我们抓到劳的把柄了 这就是啊
Why not? We got law. This is it.
不 这只是劳包庇一个神父的证据
No, this is law covering for one priest.
还有其他九十位神父逍遥法外呢
There's another 90 out there.
我知道 等我们拿到证据了再曝光他们也不迟
Yeah, we'll print that story when we get it,
但我们现在得把这个报道出来
but we gotta go with this now.
这个报道我不想仓促而行 麦克
I'm not gonna rush this story,Mike.
我们别无选择 罗比
We don't have a choice, Robby.
如果我们不赶紧报道
If we don't rush to print,
就会有人
somebody else is going
发现这些信件 抢先披露出来
to find these letters and butcher the story.
《先驱报》的乔・昆比当时就在法院蹲点呢
Joe Quimby from The Herald was at the freaking courthouse.
那我们就先写一份报道放着
So we'll write a holding
同时紧盯《先驱报》的动向
story and we'll keep our eye on The Herald.
紧盯《先驱报》的动向
Keep our eye on The Herald?
如果他们插手进来 报道出了差错的话 教会会把这事给压下去的
They run this and get it wrong, the church will bury it.
-我们现在就得报道出来 -麦克 麦克
- We gotta do this now. - Mike, Mike.
怎么了 为什么要犹豫不决呢
What? Why are we hesitating?
巴伦让我们抓劳的把柄 我们抓到了
Baron told us to get law. This is law.
巴伦是让我们揭露整个系统
Baron told us to get the system.
我们需要着眼全局
We need the full scope.
这是我们了结此事的唯一途径
That's the only thing that will put an end to this.
那我们把这拿去给本 让他来做决定
Then let's take it to Ben, let him decide.
到时候我自然会拿给他看 这由我来决定
We'll take it to Ben when I say it's time.
到时候了 罗比 是时候了
It's time, Robby! It's time!
他们早就知道了 却放任悲剧降临到孩子们身上
They knew and they let it happen. To kids!
受害者本可能是你 也可能是我
Okay? It could've been you. It could've been me.
可能是我们任何人
It could've been any of us.
我们得揭穿这些卑鄙小人
We gotta nail these scumbags.
我们得让世人知道没人能逃脱罪责
We gotta show people that nobody can get away with this.
神父不可以 红衣主教不可以 教皇也不可以
Not a priest or a cardinal or a freaking pope!
你说完了吗
You finished?
对 我说完了 你简直就是在放屁
Yeah, I am. This is bullshit.
你没事吧
You okay?
嗯
Mmm.
你好 汉西
Hey, hansi.
今天工作不顺吧 麦克
Hard day at work, Mike?
-给 -谢谢
- Here. - Thank you.
我 我 我不知道我为什么会那么生气
I-I-I-I don't know why I got so pissed off.
我觉得罗比错了
You know, I think Robby's wrong.
其实 你只是
You know, you're just--
你太关心这次报道了 麦克 大家都一样
you care about the story, Mike. We all do.
-是啊 也许吧 -嗯
- Yeah, I guess. - Hmm.
我已经不再陪我奶奶去教堂了
I stopped going to church with my Nana.
这 这太难熬了 我
It was-- it was too hard. I--
你知道吗 我坐在那里
you know, I'd be sitting there,
然后就会想起乔・克劳利或者其他人
and I would start thinking about Joe Crowley or someone else,
然后我 我就会很愤怒
and I just-- I just got so angry.
你有 你有告诉她原因吗
Did you-- did you tell her why?
她一周要去三次教堂 麦克
She goes to church three times a week, Mike.
这真的使我很恼火
It really pisses me off.
你知道吗
You know,
当我还是个小孩子的时候 我真的很喜欢去教堂
I actually really liked going to church when I was a little kid.
嗯
Mmm.
-后来为什么不去了呢 -没什么特别的原因
- Why'd you stop? - Typical shit.
但奇怪的是
But the weird thing is...
我感觉
I think I--
我总觉得没准有一天我会 我会
I think I figured that maybe one day I w-- I w--
我会再回去的
I would actually go back.
我真的 我真的有这个打算的
I was really-- I was holding on to that.
嗯
Mm-hmm.
当我看完那些信 然后
I read those letters, and it--
就好像是 心里有什么东西裂开了
and something just... cracked.
-这感觉很糟糕 -是啊
- It's a shitty feeling. - Yeah.
这种感觉很糟糕
It's a shitty feeling.
-看来你今天过得并不顺啊 -嘿 皮特
- Looks like a long day. - Hey, Pete.
很抱歉我还得打搅你
I'm sorry to make it longer.
布莱恩
Brian.
没有人能拒绝和你喝一杯吧 皮特
Has anyone ever said no to a drink with you, Pete?
嗯 当然有啊
Well, sure.
关键是得坚持邀请
But the trick is to keep asking.
-为了波士顿  -波士顿
- For Boston. - Boston.
嗯
Mmm.
那么 嗯 你是为了红衣主教的事来的吗
So, um, you here for the cardinal?
噢 不不不
Oh, no, no, no, no.
我可不敢擅自代表红衣主教 绝对不敢
I wouldn't-- I wouldn't presume to speak for the cardinal, no.
你知道的 这里有很多人非常尊敬你 罗比
You know, you got a lot of people here who respect you, Robby.
-嗯 -因为你做的事
- Yeah.  - With work you do.
-这让我挺开心的 -因为你热爱这个城市
- That's good to know. - It's 'cause you care about this place.
这也是你身为新闻人的原因 这是你的使命
It's why you do what you do. It's who you are.
但你要知道 人们现在需要教会的存在 比任何时候都需要
You know, but people need the church, more than ever right now.
你可以体会得到
You know, you can feel it.
并且红衣主教 呃
And the cardinal, uh--
你知道的 红衣主教他 也许不是完人
you know, the cardinal, he might not be perfect.
但我们不能因为几粒老鼠屎
But we can't throw out all
就否定他的杰出贡献
the good he's doing over a few bad apples.
我现在跟你提这些
Now, you know, I'm bringing
是因为我知道这都是巴伦的主意
this up to you because I know this is Baron's idea.
这是他要做的事
His agenda.
我得告诉你 我是说 说句实话
I gotta tell ya, I mean, honest to god,
他不像我们这样热爱这座城市
I mean, he doesn't care about the city the way we do.
他怎么可能呢
I mean, how could he?
这就是你们的惯用伎俩 对吗 皮特
This is how it happens, isn't it, Pete?
怎么说
What's that?
一个人去威逼利诱另一个人
A guy leans on a guy,
然后忽然间对整座城市的看法都变了
and suddenly the whole town just looks the other way.
罗比 罗比 听着
Robby. Robby. Look it.
马蒂・巴伦只是想赚点名气罢了
Marty Baron is just trying to make his mark.
他只会在这里呆上几年 然后就会升迁离开了
He's gonna be here for a couple of years and he's gonna move on.
就像他在纽约和迈阿密时一样
Just like he did in New York and Miami.
但是你又能去哪里呢
Where are you gonna go?
嗯
Hmm?
晚安 罗比 布莱恩
Good night, Robby. Brian.
-嘿 呃 皮特  -什么事
- Hey, uh, Pete. - Yeah?
呃 当我们真的报道此事时
Uh, when we do run the story,
额 我需要红衣主教的评论
uh, I'm gonna need a comment from the cardinal.
我们回头再谈 晚安 罗比
We'll talk again later. Good night, Robby.
晚安 皮特
Night, Pete.
我是罗比
Robby.
什么
What?
真的假的 什么时候
No shit. When?
好的 好
Okay. Yeah.
嘿
Hey.
怎么了
What's up?
斯威尼做出了支持我们的裁决
Sweeney ruled in our favor.
她判决将文件开封
She ruled to unseal the documents.
天哪 哈
Geez. Huh.
教会已经提起了上诉
The church has already filed an appeal.
但初审法院对此的判决仍旧有效
But the trial court ruling is generally upheld in these matters.
那我们什么时候能拿到那些文件
And when would we get the documents?
科恩也许还得花几周时间来处理
Probably takes Cohen a few weeks to rule.
然后还需要走一个校订的流程
Then there's a redaction process.
呃 我认为在一月中旬文件就能公布了
Uh, I'd say they'd be made public mid-January.
-好的 -行了
- Okay. - All right.
-谢谢 约翰  -没事
- Thanks, John. - You bet.
-你做得很棒  -谢谢
- Nice work. - Thanks.
《都市报》得写点东西出来 马蒂
Metro should run something, Marty.
这事我们不能大肆宣传
We can't run this one big.
为什么不能 这是一次意义重大的挑战修正案的胜利啊
Why wouldn't we? It's a major first amendment victory.
更别提你成功让
Not to mention, you get an
一个爱尔兰裔天主教法官来对抗教会
Irish catholic judge ruling against the church?
-这可是个了不得的先例啊 -嗯
- That's a hell of a precedent. - Mm-hmm.
我们不能让《先驱报》深挖此事
We don't want The Herald going deep on this.
为什么
Why's that?
你得先回避一下 彼得
You're gonna have to step out, Peter.
我才不回避呢
I'm not stepping out.
彼得
Peter.
-你是什么时候 呃  -几周前
- When did you, uh-- - a couple of weeks ago.
几周前
A couple of weeks?
-是的  -然后你现在才告诉我们吗
- Yeah. - And you're telling us now?
这些材料太重要了
These are substantial.
这些材料清楚地表明劳有渎职行为
They clearly show that law was negligent.
我需要更多时间
I need more time.
-我想接着调查下去  -调查什么
- I wanna keep digging. - For what?
-这就是事情真相了  -这不是事实的全部
- This is the goddamn story. - It's not the whole story.
这很棘手啊 我们没剩下多少时间了
Tough shit. We're on a clock now.
即使我们不报道斯威尼的判决结果
Even if we don't run Sweeney's ruling,
其他报社也可能会发现这些信件 抢先报道
another paper could find these letters and fuck the story.
我知道 但如果我们单独报道这些信件
Agreed. But we run these letters alone,
劳会道歉 说只发生过一次 他可以把真相掩盖起来
law apologizes, says it's a one-time thing. He can bury it.
怎么掩盖 这些信件证明了他知道罪行却毫无作为
How? These clearly show he knew and did nothing about it.
听着 我快要把全部七十个神父的丑闻挖到底了
Look, I'm close to stories on 70 priests.
我们把那些全部搞定后 再加上这些信件
We nail that, along with those letters,
就能证明此事不只是劳的过失
this is proof that this is bigger than law.
而且是整个体系的腐坏
It's the whole system.
你有足够证据证明全部神父的罪过吗
You have multiple sources confirming all those priests?
-有一部分了 我可以拿到更多 -太冒险了
- On some. I can get more. - Too risky.
如果我们不把他们每个人
If we're not buttoned up on every
挖的底朝天 教会就会挑我们的毛病
single one of them, the church will pick us apart.
我可以为我们争取到教会那边的一个证人
I think I can get us someone from the other side of the aisle.
教会内部的人吗
Somebody inside the church?
是的 一名律师
Yeah. A lawyer.
他愿意公开证明吗
Will he go on the record?
他背景很深 但值得信赖
Deep background. But he's a solid source.
雷赞德斯需要时间来写报道
Rezendes needs time to write the story.
我们不能在圣诞节披露 尤其是九・一一事件过后
We don't want to drop it at Christmas, not after 9/11.
我们可以在新年后报导
We could run it just after new year's,
赶在他们公布剩下的文件之前
before they release the rest of the documents.
好的
All right.
告诉卡内洛斯别报道这次裁决了
Tell Canellos to bury the ruling in Metro.
你有六周时间
You got six weeks.
谢谢
Thank you.
告诉麦克在圣诞节前将初稿交给我
Tell Mike I want a draft by Christmas.
我们还需要教堂方面的回应
And we need a response from lake street.
红衣主教的公关是谁 还是约翰・沃什吗
Who does PR for the cardinal? Still John Walsh?
不是 是个新人 叫唐娜・莫里西 之前在TV网任职 她还很年轻
No, somebody new. Donna Morrissey. She came from TV. She's young.
好的 去做一份引述
Good. Get a quote. We
我们得准备点劳的言论 以示公正
need something from law to appear evenhanded.
罗比 下次得提前给我提个醒
Robby, next time give me a goddamn heads-up.
好的
Will do.
罗比 真是稀客啊
Robby, what a nice surprise.
快请进
Come on in.
嘿 亲爱的 看看是谁来了
Hey, hon, look who I found outside.
凯伦 能让我们单独待会儿吗
Karen, can you give us a minute?
-当然 -见到你很高兴 凯伦
- Sure. - Good to see you, Karen.
什么事
What's up?
我快没时间了 吉姆
I'm out of time, Jim.
我们已经写好了七十位神父的丑闻报道
We've got cover-up stories on 70 priests.
但我的上级要求
But the boss isn't gonna run
必须得到你们这边的证实后才能披露
it unless I get confirmation from your side.
你疯了吗
Are you out of your mind?
拜托了 这是我们的城市啊 吉米
Come on. This is our town, Jimmy.
每个人都知道有罪恶在发生 可没人有所行动
Everybody knew something was going on, and no one did a thing.
-我们必须结束这一切 -不用你来提醒我该做什么
- We gotta put an end to it. - Don't tell me what I gotta do.
没错 我是帮这些卑鄙小人做了辩护 但那是我的职责所在 罗比
Yeah, I helped defend these scumbags, but that's my job, Robby.
我只是在尽职
I was doing my job.
是啊
Yeah.
你跟其他人一样
You and everyone else.
滚出我的房子
Get out of my house.
嘿
Hey!
你来我家就为了说这些的吗
You come to my home and lay this shit on me?
你说得对 罗比
You were right, Robby.
每个人都知道有罪恶发生
We all knew something was going on.
那你当时在哪里呢 你为什么耽误了这么久
So where were you? What took you so long?
我不知道 吉姆
I don't know, Jim.
把名单给我
Give me the list.
拉里 我们六小时后就要报道了
Larry, we're going to press in six hours.
唐娜・莫里西几小时前说
Donna Morrissey said she'd
她会打给我们 转述劳的声明
call us with a quote from law hours ago.
-我也以为 -你是什么时候跟她说的
- That's what I thought. - When did you talk to her?
-好的 好的 拉里 -好的
- Okay. Okay, Larry. - Yeah.
好 好的 这是个好消息 谢谢你 皮特
Yeah. Yeah, that's good to know. Thanks, Pete.
有什么新动向吗
Anything?
康利说唐娜・莫里西早该打电话过来的
Conley said Donna Morrissey should've called.
他刚离开教堂
He just left lake street.
是啊 拉斯基也是这么说的
Yeah, Rasky said the same thing.
这太可笑了 你觉得他们还想先下手为强
This is ridiculous. You'd think they want to get ahead of this.
我是说 他们要不提前采取行动才是傻呢
I mean, they'd be idiots not to.
我真想看看他们读了我们的报道之后的表情
I would love to see their faces when they read this thing.
星期天可是盛大的主显节呢
You know,Sunday's the feast of the epiphany.
那挺合适的
That seems appropriate.
我是麦克・雷赞德斯
Mike Rezendes.
你好 唐娜
Hey, Donna.
感谢你的来电 是啊
Thanks for calling. Yeah,
如果你有空的话 我想问几个问题
I just had a few questions if you have a minute.
什么
What?
-怎么了  -又有个形容词使用不当
- What? - Another adjective.
-有什么消息吗 -劳刚刚回绝了我们的提问
- Anything? - Law just turned us down.
天啊
Jesus Christ.
我刚和唐娜・莫里西通完电话
I just got off the phone with Donna Morrissey.
引述如下 “我们连问题是什么
She said, quote, "We don't even
都没有兴趣知道” 转述完毕
want to know what the questions are," End quote.
-她真的这样说吗 -是的
- She really said that? - Yeah.
嗯 这样也行
Well, that ought to do it.
“教会对于《环球报》的疑问
"The church had no interest
表示毫无兴趣”
in knowing what the globe's questions would be."
把这句话加到重点内容前面 还有别的吗
Work it in somewhere before the jump. Anything else?
马特想把信件放到网上
Matt wants to put the letters
以供读者自行查阅
online so the readers can see for themselves.
我们可以在文章最后附上网址链接
We can run the url at the bottom of the article.
-这样挺方便的 -好的
- It's pretty straightforward. - Okay.
我们还可以把办公室的专线电话
We also put the spotlight tip
放在文末 方便大家打进来
line at the end of the story so people can call in.
直接打到我们办公室来
Goes directly to our office.
我和马特也可以一早就来 以便接电话
Matt and I can go in in the morning in case we get any calls.
嗯 我更担心接待处的电话
Yeah, I'm more concerned about the phones at reception.
在我们报道了波特案之后
After we ran the Porter case,
电话中心好几周都忙得不可开交
the message centers were tied up for weeks.
-这是个问题 -纠察员也是个问题
- It's a real problem. - There were picketers too.
大家都很忙
Lots of 'em.
我会跟理查德谈安保工作和电话问题的
I'll talk to Richard about the security and the phones.
呃 后续报道要怎样进行
Uh, how are we coming on the folo story?
嗯 我们把全部七十个神父的报道都搞定了
Well, we've nailed down multiple stories on 70 priests.
-全部七十个吗  -嗯
- All 70? - Mm-hmm.
而且拿到了罗比线人的证明 我们随时可以报道了
And with confirmation from Robby's source, we're ready to go.
我们下周内可以写好初稿
We can have a draft next week.
罗比 那位给你提供消息的人 我们可以重访吗
Robby, that source of yours, is it something we could revisit?
可能有点困难
It might be tough.
那他给几十个下贱的神父
But he has no problem helping
打掩护时就不困难了吗
the church protect dozens of dirty priests.
-那家伙可真卑鄙 -他是一名律师 他只是在做他应做的
- Guy's a scumbag. - He's a lawyer. He's doing his job.
-他就是教会雇佣的骗子 -他是在助纣为虐
- He's a shill for the church. - He knew and did nothing.
他本可以早点说出来 也许还能救回几条命
He could've said something years ago, maybe saved some lives.
那我们呢
What about us?
-这是什么意思 -我们早就有不少线索了
- What's that supposed to mean? - We had all the pieces.
为什么没能早点发掘真相呢
Why didn't we get it sooner?
-我们哪里有很多线索了 -我们有萨维亚诺
- We didn't have all the pieces. - We had saviano.
巴雷特和吉欧根
We had Barrett. We had Geoghan.
还有地下室里那些人名录
We had the directories in the basement.
这样说吧 我们现在有了结果
You know what? We got it now.
罗比 这个报道需要聚焦小组的努力
Robby, the story needed spotlight.
麦克 这个组1970年就成立了
Mike, spotlight's been around since 1970.
那又怎样 我们又没办法预知未来 没人可以
So what? We couldn't see the scope of this. No one could.
罗比 这是由一个该死的神父牵扯出来的
Robby, this started with one goddamn priest.
麦克利什几年前寄来过一封信 检举了二十个神父
Macleish sent us a letter on 20 priests years ago.
萨夏找到了剪报
Sacha found the clip.
你开什么玩笑 二十名神父吗
You freaking kidding? Twenty priests?
什么时候
When?
呃 就在波特案之后 93年12月
Uh, just after Porter. December '93.
我们把这事给了《都市报》 没有进行后续报道
We buried the story in Metro. No folo.
是你吗
That was you?
你那时是《都市报》的主管
You were Metro.
是的 是我
Yeah. That was me.
我那时刚接管 完全不记得有这回事
I'd just taken over. I don't remember it at all.
但是 没错
But yeah.
嗯
Um,
我能不能 呃 说几句
can I, uh, say something here?
有时候我们很容易就忘记了
Sometimes it's easy to forget
很多时候我们都在黑暗边缘徘徊
that we spend most of our time stumbling around in the dark.
一旦光明降临
Suddenly a light gets turned on,
罪人自会接受惩罚
and there's a fair share of blame to go around.
我无法对调任此地之前的事情作过多评论
I can't speak to what happened before I arrived,
但是 呃 你们所有人都为这次的报道贡献颇多
but, uh, all of you have done some very good reporting here.
这类报道能够迅速引起读者
Reporting that I believe is gonna have an immediate
大范围的关注
and considerable impact on our readers.
于我而言 这就是我们新闻行业的价值所在
For me, this kind of story is why we do this.
我说过
Having said that,
劳主教和天主教社区
cardinal law and the catholic community
肯定会对此事有强烈的反应
are gonna have a very strong response to this.
所以 如果你们需要休息
So if you need a moment,
完全没问题
you've earned it.
但是 呃
But, uh,
你们周一早上必须到岗
I will need you back here Monday morning,
全力准备 专心工作
focused and ready to do your job.
-走吗 -好的
- Leaving? - Yeah.
我 呃 刚刚接到了红衣主教的电话
I, uh, just got a call from the cardinal.
真的吗 为什么
Really. Why?
他想亲自告诉我 他决定不对此事做任何评论
He wanted to tell me personally that he decided not to comment.
他还说 他愿意 呃 增加给我的好处
Yeah. Said he wanted to, uh, extend me that courtesy.
天哪 那家伙可真有胆量 你是怎么说的
Jesus, the balls on that guy. What did you say?
我跟他说 他这么做是错的
I told him he was making a
而且我们肯定会把这件事报道出来
mistake and that we were gonna run the story.
我们当然要报道这事
Damn right we're gonna run it.
萨夏 能给我倒杯水吗
Sacha, can I have a drink of water?
好的 没问题 奶奶 好的
Yeah. Sure, Nana. Yeah.
我能留着这份报纸吗
Can I keep this?
当然
Sure.
我认为应该先拿给你看看
I thought you should see it first.
谢谢你把它拿给我
Thank you for bringing it by.
现在 我还有几位委托人的事要处理
Now, I have some clients I have to attend to.
好的
Yeah.
两个孩子都被侵犯了
Both kids were abused.
牙买加平原 两周前发生的
Jamaica Plain. Two weeks ago.
继续 加油吧 雷赞德斯先生
Keep... doing your work, Mr. Rezendes.
-你们好呀 -你好
- Hello. - Hello.
你们好吗
How are you guys doing?
-很好 谢谢  -很好
- Good, thanks. - Good.
-嘿 -早上好
- Hey. - Good morning.
睡得好吗
How'd you sleep?
不是很好 你呢
Not very well. You?
-我几个月没睡好觉了 -嗯
- I haven't slept well for months. - Mmm.
噢 谢谢 我 呃 我开始写书了
Oh, thanks. I, uh, actually started writing.
-写书 -是的 我一直在写一本书
- Writing? - Yeah, I've been working on a book.
这能转移我的注意力
Gives me something else to focus on.
-什么题材的书 -惊悚
- What kind of book? - Horror.
是的
Yeah.
这里是聚焦小组
Spotlight.
是的
Yeah.
好的 没问题 能否 呃 告知下你的姓名
Yeah, of course. Can I, uh-- can I get your name, please?
-你知道今天是星期天吧 -反正没时间打高尔夫了
- You do know it's Sunday, right? - Couldn't get a tee time.
-今天没有纠察员 -是啊
- No picketers. - Yeah.
可能还在教堂吧
Probably still at church.
你好 琳达 挺安静的诶
Hey, Linda. It's quiet, huh?
是啊 最轻松的一次加班了
Yeah. Easiest overtime I ever made.
电话一次都没响过
Phone hasn't rung once.
马蒂把我的两个手下都调到聚焦小组去了
Marty sent two of mine down to spotlight.
-文章写得很棒 伙计们 -谢谢
- Great article, guys. - Thank you.
-谢谢 -聚焦小组
- Thanks. - Spotlight?
好的 是的
Okay. Yep.
这里是聚焦小组 有什么可以帮您的吗
Spotlight. Can I help you?
电话已经响了一上午了
Phones have been ringing all morning.
这里是聚焦小组
Spotlight.
-麦克 能接下那个吗 -好 好的
- Mike, can you grab that? - Yeah, yeah.
他们几乎全是受害者 罗比
They're almost all victims, Robby.
-很抱歉让您久等了 -我是萨夏・法伊弗
- I'm sorry to make you wait. - Sacha Pfeiffer.
抱歉 你能否
I'm sorry-- can you--
是的 你可以来这里找我
Yes, you can reach me here.
这里是聚焦小组
This is spotlight.
我能记一下你的名字吗
Can I get your name?
你之后还有和住在那的人
Did you happen to have any
联系吗
contact with anybody that was there afterward?
你记得当时是哪一年吗
Do you remember what year this was?
是哪个教区呢
Which parish was it?
这里是聚焦小组
This is spotlight.